FX的平方取N  Y果是DX
Mod f- x- square d- x.
下次上n前做完
So please finish Percival for next time.
大Wrm已W^  但}o妨
I know many of you had this as undergraduates but it won't hurt to brush up.
xx  史蒂芬
Thank you Steven.
走廊黑板上有高傅立~算式
I also put an advanced Fourier system on the main hallway chalkboard.
希望W期Y束前有人解
I'm hoping that one of you might prove it by the end of the semester.
解出淼娜瞬恢挥泻贸煽
Now the person to do so will not only be in my good graces...
可因此o名利p收
but also go on to fame and fortune by having their accomplishment recorded and their name printed.
留名麻省理工W院
in the auspicious M.I.T. Tech.
之前解答包括Z得主  菲德章得主
Former winners include Nobel laureates Field's medal winners...
天文物理W家
renowned astrophysicists...
有卑v的麻省理工教授
and lowly M.I.T. professors.
就@  如果有}
Well that's all. If you have any questions...
我相信姆解答
I'm sure that Tom has the answers.
威
Hi Will.
你好?
Kirsten how you doing?
很好  你呢?
I'm all right. How are you?
好
Good.
我昨晚]上P西
I didn't get on Cathy last night.
- ]有?  - ]有
- No?  - No.
槭颤N?
Why not?
不知道  P西!
I don't know. Cathy!
致?
What?
槭颤N不我爽
Why didn't you give me none of that nasty little hoochie- woochie...
- 就像平r那?  - 去你的
- you usually throw at me?  - Oh fuck you...
有你的mv
and your Irish curse Chuckie.
我才不要榱诵±隙_腿
Like I'd waste my energy spreadin' my legs for that Tootsie Roll dick?
回家自己打手去吧
Go home and give it a tug yourself.
小老二!
Tootsie Roll!
T- Toots!
她少一w牙
She's missin' a tooth Will.
她皮w也有}
She's got skin problems. I don't...
r且到^砟Ω八成娶她
Plus it's like 5- to- 2 Morgan ends up marryin' her you know what I mean?
朋友的准老婆只能上状
There's only so many times you can bang your friend's future wife. It's wrong.
你去哪?
Where you goin'?
我要走了
I'm gonna take off.
我操  才十c就要走?
Fuck you you're takin' off. It's like what 10:00?
我累了
No I'm tired.
mv?
Irish curse?
你懂什N?
She don't know. There ain't no Irish curse.
e老故意打到我
Out! Stop pressuring me back.
不要再靠近本景
Stop crowding the plate!
你x哪?
Which one will it be?
你被起V  你知道?
You're gonna get charged you know that?
你以槲遗履惆?
You think I'm afraid of you you big fuck?
是你他的太靠近本景
You're crowdin' the fuckin' plate.
w西下Y拜在哈佛的酒吧
Hey uh Casey's bouncin' up a bar at Harvard next week.
我去
We should go up there.
到那致
What are we gonna do up there?
不知道
I don't know.
去整明小孩  你很擅L
We'll fuck up some smart kids. Probably fit right in.
臭痞子
Ow! Fuckin' punk.
- 怎?  你很凶?  - 戆!
- Oh what's up? You still tough?  - Come on!
戆    s翰  戆
Come on. Come on. That's it.
- {勃教授?  - 是的
- Professor Lambeau?  - Yes?
我是你的用理nW生
I'm in your applied theories class. We're all up at the math and science building.
^
Come here.
今天Y拜六
It's Saturday.
除非你今晚陪我喝酒
Unless you wanna have a drink with me tonight.
或S吧
Maybe.
但我急著想弄清楚
We just couldn't wait until Monday to find out.
弄清楚什N?
Find out what?
是l解出傅立~算式
Who proved the theorem.
完全正_
This is correct.
l解的?  芸?
Who did this? Jack?
不是我
It wasn't me.
尼米S?
Nemesh?
怎N可能
N- No way.
快  桃  就是F在!
Come on Joey now!
他快]力了  把他值
Billy McNamara's up.
快c!
Come on kid!
桃  快跑
Joey dig it out! Dig it out!
快放下  @硬
Bring it down Mac! That's how to do it!
做得好  二  往二九
Attaboy! Take two Mac.
穿ly的俏屁股女人是l?
Hey Morgan who's the girl with the striped pants? She's got a nice ass.
那屁股真不
Yeah that's a real nice ass.
她跟l一起?
Who's the guy she's with?
是他的卡~  我他
That fuckin' guinea. I hate that little bitch.
威JR他
Will knows him.
你JR他?
Yeah I do.
死的卡~
Yeah fuckin' Carmine Scarpaglia.
他幼稚@r把我揍得好K
That guy used to beat the shit out of me in kindergarten.
那人?
That guy?
恩
Yeah.
操他的  去弄c|西吃吧
Fuck this. Let's get some food.
摩根  你不跟她v?
Oh what Morgan you're not gonna go talk to her?
去她的
Fuck her.
我可吃大h堡
I could go for a Whopper.
到P利去吧
Let's go to Kelly's.
才不要去
Morgan I'm not goin' to Kelly's.
你只是喜g那旱耐赓u女孩
Just 'cause you like the take- out girl.
而且要多@15分路
It's 15 minutes out of our way.
我他的挪不出15分?
What the fuck are we gonna do? We can't spare 15 minutes?
大h堡
Double burger.
查克  我有大h堡
Chuck I had a double burger.
]嘴  我知道你c什N
Would you shut the fuck up! I know what you ordered. I was there.
那就把我的三明治o我
So give me my fuckin' sandwich.
什N叫你的三明治?  是我I的
What do you mean your sandwich? I bought it.
你身上有多少X?
Morgan how much money you got on you?
I霜淇淋就有零X了嘛
I said I'd get change when I get the snow cone.
h堡o我  e@N
I said that when we pulled up. Give me my sandwich and stop bein' a prick.
好  把身上的一毛六o我
All right well give me your fuckin' 16 cents that you got on you now.
我你他的分期付款Ih堡
We'll put your fuckin' sandwich on layaway.
h堡[@
Here we go. Keep it right up here for ya.
我你分期付款
We'll put you on a program.
每天六分X
Every day you come in here with your six cents.
L末o你h堡
At the end of the week you get your sandwich.
你怎N@N混蛋?
Are you gonna be an asshole?
你他的以槲屹u慈h堡啊
What am I fuckin' sandwich welfare?
你建立良好信用
I think you should establish a good line of credit.
就像你I沙l那
Like how you bought your couch...payment plans.
得你每天存十KX?
Remember how your mother brought in ten dollars every day for a year?
最後她K於I到沙l了
She finally got her couch Rent- A- Center style.
可以把食物o我了?
Can I have my food please?
把你的大h堡拿去
Here's your fuckin' double burger.
等等  查克
Hey hold up Chuck.
慢下
Slow it down.
怎N了?
Who do we got?
不知道
I don't know yet.
算了  威
Come on Will.
15分前才在公@看到他
We seen the guy 15 minutes ago.
要扁他r就扁了
We should've fight him then. We're eatin' our snacks now.
]嘴  摩根  你也下去
Shut up Morgan you're goin'.
我才不去
I'm not goin'.
那就e去
So don't go.
我不去
I'm not goin'.
你他的o我去  摩根
Fuckin' go Morgan.
我跟你v  擅炔L出去
Let me tell you somethin'. If you're not out there in two fuckin' seconds
等我扁完他  就扁你
when I'm done with them you're next.
卡~  是我  威  得?
Carmine it's me Will. Remember?
我是幼稚@同W
We went to kindergarten together.
- 他在致?  - 他把他扁K了
- Fuckin' let's go man.  - Step on his fuckin' head.
叫那砘镒∈
Get his ass on the ground. Stop that motherfucker.
混蛋  去死吧!
Motherfucker die!
威  l子  快走
Will! Will come on!
l子...快
Will come on. Let's go. Let's go.
e激  e激
Easy brother easy.
怎N?  xx你出
Hey fellas thanks for comin' out.
^!
Come here!
操
Ah. Fuck.
@是做暨是班大了?
Is it just my imagination or has my class grown considerably?
如果不是在做舻脑...
Well by no stretch of my imagination...
你是砺我vn
do I believe you've all come here to hear me lecture.
或想知道神秘W奇才是l
Rather to ascertain the identity of the mystery math magician.
沉默的天才  出眍I吧
So without further adieu come forward silent rogue and receive thy prize.
抱歉^失望了
Well I'm sorry to disappoint my spectators but...
看斫裉觳揭粤
it seems there will be no unmasking here today.
我和同事Q定再下鹛
However uh my colleagues and l have conferred...
外面黑板上有}目
and there is a problem on the board right now...
我花了赡rg才解_
that took us more than two years to prove.
沉默的天才再解解看
So let this be said: The gauntlet has been thrown down...
全w教授已溆薪獯
but the faculty have answered and answered with vigor.
r提?
Hey when's the arraignment?
下星期
Next week.
Σ黄
Sorry.
你在做什N?
What are you doing?
Σ黄
Sorry.
你不能在人家的方程式上Tf
That's people's work. You can't graffiti here.
你e走!
Don't you walk away from me!
去你的!
Hey fuck you!
e耍明  你叫什N名字?
Oh you're a clever one. What's your name?
我的天
Oh my God.
好像是Φ
Looks right.
要多智障才被_除?
Will how retarded do you gotta be to get fired from that job?
在屋子e叩赜心屈Ny?
I mean how hard is it to push a motherfuckin' broom around?
你B叩囟被_除
Mitch you got fired from pushin' a fuckin' broom.
那是因楣芾黼A又亟M
I got fired 'cause management was restructuring.
重M智障旱盗
Yeah restructuring the amount of retards they had workin' for 'em.
]嘴  你被_除的次蹈多
Shut up. You get canned more than tuna bitch.
起aF在我有工作
At least I got a motherfuckin' job right now don't I?
是啊
Yeah.
威  你楹伪婚_除?
Why'd you get fired Will? Come on.
管理A重M
Management was restructuring.
我舅舅或S能o你工作
My uncle could probably get you on a demo team.
可以?
Can he do that?
你耍我  我昨天^你
You kiddin' me! I asked you yesterday if I could get a job.
我昨天告V你不行
And I told you "no" yesterday.
怎N?  w斯
- What's up Casey?  - What's up Case?  - What's up Big Case?
坐@
Let's sit over here.
@就是哈佛酒吧?
Oh this is...this is a Harvard bar huh?
我以上有方程式呢
I thought there'd be like equations and shit on the wall.
我要一氐暄e最好的啤酒
I will take a pitcher of the finest lager in the house.
和
Timeout.
我要去泡吧台的哈佛辣妹
I'm gonna have to bust a little move on them Harvard hotties down there at the bar.
- 看我的吧  - 臀
- Work some magic.  - Get some potion for us.
- 你好  - 你好
- Oh hello.  - Oh hello.
你好?
Hi. How are ya?
好
Fine.
晌幻琅...
So do you ladies uh...
常?
Come here often?
我常?  我...
Do I come here? I come here a bit.
偶
I'm here you know from time to time.
你在@耗
Do you go to school here?
Yep.
就是嘛  我想我跟你同班
Yeah that's it. I think I had a class with you.
是?  哪一班?
Oh yeah. What class?
v史
History.
或S
Maybe.
]e
Yes I think that's what it was.
你可能不JR我  我磉@
You don't necessarily...may not remember me. You know I like it here.
K不表示我是天才  但我是很明
It doesn't mean 'cause I go here I'm a genius. I am very smart.
你好?
Hey how's it goin'? How are ya?
好  你呢?
Good. How ya doin'?
你f你在哪一班?
What class did you say that was?
v史
History.
v史?  那一定是概n程
Just history? It must have been a survey course then.
-   是概n程  - ]e
Yeah it was. It was surveys.  - Right.
你上上看  不e的n
You should check it out. It's a good course. It'd be a good class.
你X得那堂n怎N?
How'd you like that course?
老f  我X得很基A
You know frankly I found that class you know rather elementary.
基A
Elementary.
肯定是的
You know I don't doubt that it was.
我得那堂n了
I uh I remember that class.
就在休息和午餐之g
It was um... It was just between recess and lunch.
克拉克  你走_啦
Clark why don't you go away?
放pc
Why don't you relax?
走_啦
Why don't you go away?
我跟我的新朋友很_心
I'm just havin' fun with my new friend.
有什N}?
Are we gonna have a problem?
]}
No no no no. There's no problem here.
只是想教你於市鼋...
I was just hoping you might give me some insight into the evolution...
在南部殖民地l展的看法
of the market economy in the southern colonies.
我主在革命前...
My contention is that prior to the Revolutionary War...
南方殖民地的形B...
the economic modalities especially in the southern colonies...
最m切被刻...
could most aptly be characterized as...
- r地  - 我碚f删
- agrarian precapitalist.  - Let me tell you somethin'.
那然是你的c  新生嘛
Of course that's your contention. You're a first- year grad student.
才念完R克斯主x
You just got finished readin' some Marxian historian... Pete Garrison probably...
下月念到雷蒙的c你更深信不疑
You're gonna be convinced of that till next month when you get to James Lemon.
然後你到S吉尼州及e州...
Then you're gonna be talkin' about how the economies of Virginia and Pennsylvania...
在1740年如何企I化cY本主x化...
were entrepreneurial and capitalist way back in 1740.
一直持m到明年你反c伍德...
That's gonna last until next year. You're gonna be in here regurgitatin' Gordon Wood...
大革命前跬邪...
talkin' about you know the prerevolutionary utopia...
和事TY本形成的影
and the capital- forming effects of military mobilization.
事上我反@^c
Well as a matter of fact I won't.
因槲榈峦耆低估了社...
Because Wood drastically underestimates the impact of...
伍德低估了富的社差...
Wood drastically underestimates the impact of social distinctions...
尤其是^承富
predicated upon wealth especially inherited wealth.
@是你木S克斯x到的c
You got that from Vickers
艾群就I分析  98  Σ?
Work in Essex County. Page 98 right?
我也x^
I read that too.
你要剽`整本?
Were you gonna plagiarize the whole thing for us?
@些c你有人想法?
Do you have any thoughts of your own on this matter?
你跑到酒吧砀哒中的c
Or is that your thing? You come into a bar. You read some obscure passage.
假b是自己的^c
Then pretend... pawn it off as your own.
就榱伺萱  糗我朋友?
As your own idea just to impress some girls? Embarrass my friend?
你的可悲是在五十年後
See the sad thing about a guy like you is in 50 years
你才_始t解
you're gonna start doin' some thinkin' on your own.
生命中有杉事是_定的
You're gonna come up with the fact that there are two certainties in life.
一是e只打高空
One: Don't do that.
二是你花一f五所受的教育...
And two: You dropped 150 grand on a fuckin' education...
用一K五就能在D^得到
you could've got for $1.50 in late charges at the public library.
但我有文{
Yeah but I will have a degree.
你s只能在我去滑雪俚赝局...
And you'll be servin' my kids fries at a drive...
u薯lo我的小孩
through on our way to a skiing trip.
或S吧  起a我不抄u逼e人的
Maybe but at least I won't be unoriginal.
不爽可以到外面解Q
If you have a problem with that we could step outside. We could figure it out.
不  ]事  很酷
No man there's no problem. It's cool.
酷?
It's cool?
你他的酷懒
Damn right it's cool.
F在喜g我了吧
How do you like me now?
那小子明^
My boy's wicked smart.
才砣分就[平一傻蛋
I just spent three minutes in this fuckin' place and run into a barney huh?
我  有了
There it is.
- 吉米  你好  - 她可真棒
- Nice to meet you.  - They were fine man.
我差c就要把到她  Y果比利|怒她
I was gonna close the deal but then Chuck...Billy insulted one of 'em...
辣妹就f我^快d了  又太胖
The heavyset girl said I had a receding hairline and I was a few pounds overweight.
我就f"去你的"
And I was like "Go fuck yourself."
我什N都]f
I swallowed a bug.
你是白V
You're an idiot.
什N
What?
你是白V
You're an idiot.
我坐在那整整45分...
I've been sitting over there for 45 minutes...
等你^泶钣
waiting for you to come and talk to me.
但我累了  我得回家了
But I'm tired now and I have to go home.
我不能再坐著等你
I couldn't sit there anymore waiting for you.
我是威
I'm Will.
史Pm
Skylar.
- 史Pm  - α
- Skylar.  - Oh and by the way
那人  ~可波D二
that guy over there... Michael Bolton clone...
跟我不是一的
He wasn't sitting with us so to speak.
- 我知道  我看得出  - 那就好
- I know. I kinda got that impression.  - Good. Okay.
我得走了
Well I've got to go.
我要早起花XI文{
Gotta get up early and waste some more money on my overpriced education.
我不是指你
No I didn't mean you.
]PS
That's all right.
@是我的  也S有空可以喝杯咖啡
There's my number. Maybe we can go out for coffee sometime.
好  或S聚在一起吃焦糖
All right yeah. Maybe we can just get together and eat a bunch of caramels.
什N意思?
What do you mean?
那和喝咖啡一芤
When you think about it it's as arbitrary as drinkin' coffee.
是
Oh. Yeah. Okay.
好的
Uh right then.
Yo!
兄弟!
- 去你的!  - 我才去你的
- Fuck you bitch!  - Fuck you.
那些傻旁谀沁
There goes them fuckin' barneys right now with his skiin' trip.
等等
Hold on.
我扁那混蛋
We should've beat that old bitch's ass.
你喜g青O果甜甜圈?
Do you like apples?
- 是的  - 喜g?
- Yeah.  - Yeah?
我得到她的
Well I got her number!
你s只能吃甜甜圈
How do you like them apples?
Come.
打_了  @是大枪芾硎?
Excuse me? Is this the Buildings and Grounds office?
有何F
Yeah. What can I do for you?
我要找在@e打工的W生
I just need the name of a student who works here.
]W生替我做事
No students work for me.
你查一下
Could you please check?
有人在我那亲鍪  大概L@N高
I have this guy who works in my building. He's about this high.
你在滋?
Which one is your building?
- 二  - 二
- Two.  - Two. Building two.
如果有|西失`我知道
Look if anything was stolen I should know about it.
不是那
No it's nothing like that.
我只是要找他
I just need his name.
除非你投V  否t不告V你
I can't give you his name unless you have a complaint.
@位是{勃教授
This is Professor Lambeau.
@位是海斯教授
And this is Professor Hayes.
姆  拜
Tom please.
@很重要  拜
This is important. Please.
威今天]上班
Will didn't show for work today.
他透^PO找到@份工作  你可以打o他
Got this job through his P.O. You can call him.
P.O.?
^o人
Yeah. Parole officer.
xx
Thank you.
混蛋
Asshole.
法官先生  @溯及1789年的司法判例
There is a lengthy legal precedent Your Honor going back to 1789
被告可φ府挝灰求自l
whereby a defendant can claim self- defense against an agent of the government...
如果e邮楸Ｗo自由  抗拒暴政制裁的
if that act is deemed a defense against tyranny a defense of liberty.
法官先生  比在1887年f^
Your Honor Henry Ward Beecher in Proverbs from the Plymouth Pulpit 1887 said quote...
- 1887?  F在20世o了  - 抱歉
- 1887? This is the 20th century.  - Excuse me. Excuse me.
他在嘲弄法庭
He's gonna make a mockery.
法xc我樽约恨qo之
I am afforded the right to speak in my own defense sir.
同r法x予我自由的嗔
By the Constitution of the United States. This guarantees my liberty.
不用你教我法l例
Don't tell me about the Constitution.
自由是一人呼吸的嗬
"Liberty  " in case you've forgotten is a soul's right to breathe.
o法人呼吸的法律太烂C
When it cannot take a long breath laws are girded too tight.
不自由  人就是行谱呷
Without liberty man is a syncope.
什N?
Man is a what?
出同前  法官先生
Ibid. Your Honor.
到我  我在@坐了十分...
Son my turn. I've been sitting here for ten minutes...
看著你的罪  我不敢相信
now lookin' over this rap sheet of yours. I just can't believe it.
93年6月  9月故意害
June '93 assault. September '93 assault.
偷  94年2月
Grand theft auto February of '94.
你引述  RcR的a
Where apparently you defended yourself and had the case thrown out by citing...
K以自我qo此案g回
"free property rights of horse and carriage" from 1798.
真可笑  95年1月  扮成T警
Joke. January '95 impersonating an officer.
害  `I  拒捕  全g回
Mayhem theft resisting. All overturned.
我知道你住^寄B家庭
I'm also aware that you've been through several foster homes.
因受虐而钠渲腥搬出
The state removed you from three because of serious physical abuse.
e的法官是P心你
You know another judge might care.
但你打T警  就得坐牢
But you hit a cop. You're going in.
不准提出抗告  保金五f
Motion to dismiss is denied. $50  000 bail.
xx
Thank you.
起立
Rise.
喂?
Hello?
史Pm?
Uh Skylar?
我是威
Hey uh it's Will.
- l?  - 威
- Who?  - It's Will.
你前商煸诰瓢膳龅降哥
You know the really funny good- looking guy you met at the bar the other night.
我不得有碰到@拥娜
I don't recall meeting anyone who matches that description. I think I'd remember.
好吧  是那h陋o比又]牙...
Oh all right you got me. It's the ugly obnoxious toothless loser...
整夜p著你不放的U物
who got hammered and wouldn't leave you alone all night.
威!  我起砹
Oh Will! I remember.
你好  我在想你不打
How are you? I was wondering if you'd call me.
我一直在想...
Yeah look I was wondering...
怎N?
Yo what's up baby?
稍等
Hold on one second.
怎?    想上我?
What you doing? Want some of my ass?
赫芙  我得你  在少年Oz^  你好?
Herve I remember you from juvi. How you doing?
致?  去你的
What you doing?
Σ黄
Oh yeah sorry about that.
我在想...也S@Y拜可以聚一聚
I was wonderin' maybe we could get together sometime this week.
坐在咖啡座吃c焦糖
Sit out at a cafe. Maybe have some caramels.
起砗馨
Oh that sounds wonderful.
可以?
Yeah?
可以  你在哪e?
Yeah sure. Where are you?
我站的地方有c糟...
Uh well actually this is just a shot in the dark...
你那嚎不是看守所吧
but uh there's no chance that you're pre- law is there?
坐
Have a seat.
xx
Thank you.
很高d跟你v
Nice talking to ya.
你他的想致?
What the fuck do you want?
我是苈逅{勃
I'm Gerald Lambeau.
你叫他L蛋的那教授
Professor you told to fuck himself.
找我致?
Well what the fuck do you want?
我跟法官^
I've spoken to the judge.
他同意在我Oo之下  放你出去
And he's agreed to release you under my supervision.
真的?
Really?
是的
Yeah.
但有l件
Under two conditions.
哪?
What are those?
第一  你每L要跟我碰面
First condition is that you meet with me every week.
做什N?
What for?
和你W
Go over the proof you're working on.
看你做些更高的...M合W
Get into some more advanced...combinatorial mathematics.
有限W
Finite math.
好像很有趣
Sounds like a real hoot.
第二  你要看心理t生
And the second condition is that...that you see a therapist.
由我每L作u估蟾
I'm responsible to submit reports on those meetings.
如果你不及格...
If you fail to meet with any of those conditions...
照铀湍慊碜牢
you will have to serve time.
好  W我接受  但我不看去他的心理t生
All right. I'll do the math but I'm not gonna meet with any fuckin' therapist.
@比蹲牢房好  不是?
It's better than spending that time in jail isn't it?
我看^你的
I read your book.
你提到有病人克的}...
And "Mike" was havin' the same problems...
事上和C券IIT查克一
that "Chad  " the stockbroker was havin'.
f得很准  很好
Absolutely right. Right on the button. Good for you Will.
非常好
Very nice.
xx
Thank you.
威  有P毫...
Will the pressures...and I'm not judging them.
我不是武嗟刭N你嘶`
I'm not labeling them.
但它破牧四愕力
But they are destroying your potential.
e再鹤  耍蠢  吹擂
No more shenanigans. No more tomfoolery. No more ballyhoo.
你f得
You're right.
天哪  我知道
God I know.
要[不容易    多vc
You're not gonna get off that easily. Come on Will. A bit more.
我有做^一些事
Well I mean I do do things you know?
哪N事?
What...What kind of things?
我做^...你知道...我躲避人群
I do things that you know I mean I hide from people.
你躲避?
You hide do you?
不  我也去一些地方交朋友
No no. I mean I like... I go places. I interact.
真的?  哪N地方
Really? What sort of places?
一些酒吧
Just certain clubs.
再  很好  哪N酒吧?
More. That's nice. Yes. What sort of clubs?
像是"幻想"
Like uh like Fantasy.
不e的地方
Fantasy.
好  f下去
that's nice. A bit more.
一M去整人就被音钒
It's something like when you get in there the music like owns you.
浩菀  砰...
It's like that house music. It's like...Bom- bom- bom
你就_始跳舞...
You know you start dancin'. It's just...
是的
Yes.
[m你是同性俸茈y?
Do you find it hard to hide the fact that you're gay?
你在f什N?
What are you talking about? What?
兄弟
Look buddy.
擅肭澳湎蛭
Two seconds ago you were ready to give me a jump.
?  你...
A jump? Are you...
很抱歉你失望了  威
I'm terribly sorry to disappoint you.
]PS  我不在乎你尼崦嫔
Hey I don't have a problem with it. I don't care if you putt from the rough.
尼崦嫔夏?  你在v什N?
What are you...P...Putting from the rough? What on earth are you talking about?
困y的定理就像性感的交曲
A difficult theorem could be like a symphony. It's very erotic.
你找e人  我付不
You go somewhere else. I can't handle this.
亨利
Thank you Henry.
我不能再做@N公服
Hi Gerry. You know something? I can't do this pro bono work anymore.
不值得
It's just not...It's not worth it.
怎N了?
What happened?
我要上
Well I'm going on national television next week.
]空告V你  更e提@胡言yZ的子
I mean I haven't got time to tell you much less talk to that raving looney in there.
他肯定是了
An absolute lunatic he is.
亨利
Henry.
好  你在你床上
Okay you are in your bed Will.
你q?
Now how old are you?
七q
Seven.
你看到什N?
What do you see?
我房e有|西
Something's in my room.
是什N?
What is it?
是人形  在我^上P旋
It's like a...It's a figure. It's hoverin' over me.
你在安全的地方  威
You are in a safe place Will.
下I  他在摸我
It's t...It's touchin' me.
他摸你哪e?
Where is it touching you?
摸我那下I
It's touching me down there
我很o
And I'm nervous.
不必o
You don't have to be nervous Will.
我_始跳舞  好美
We start dancin' and dancin'. It's just beautiful.
因槿章淝翱梢宰
'cause we can make a lot of love before the sun goes down.
火w舞
Skyrockets in flight
午後g
Afternoon delight
老天
Jesus.
抱歉
I'm sorry Rich.
瑞克  我跳舞
Come on Rich!
我有更重要的事情要做
I have better things to do with my time.
一支舞就好了嘛!
Come on! One dance!
你把我催眠了
You really hypnotized me you know?
看在老天份上  威
For God's sake Will.
致?  他走了不能怪我
What? Oh come on. He left. You can't pin that on me.
你得跟@些人合作
I told you to cooperate with these people.
看著...
Look...
我的眼睛
into my eyes.
出去
Get out Will.
我不需要治
I don't need therapy.
蛄  出去!
That's enough. Get out!
我早上打^o梅...
I called Mel Weintraub this morning to see...
有用?
Oh what's the use?
你想怎N做?
What do you want to do?
有人
Well there's someone.
是l?
Who is he?
他是我大W室友
He used to be my uh... my roommate in college.
信任
Trust. Very important in a relationship.
在感情上和R床上都很重要
It's also very important in a clinical situation.
楹涡湃於突破患者心防...
Why is trust the most important thing...
是最重要的PI?
in making a breakthrough with a client?
莫琳  e老著嘴  n
Maureen stop the oral fixation for a moment and join us.
S尼
Vinnie.
因樾湃尉褪巧命
Because uh... Trust is uh... Trust is life.
很深W  xx你
Wow. That's very deep. Thank you Vinnie.
你抄你弟弟的P?
Next time get the notes from your brother.
]有
No.
若病患不信任你
If a patient doesn't feel safe enough trust you.
就不坦\相
Then they won't be honest with you.
治λ碚f就毫o意x
Then there's really no point for them being in therapy.
不信任你就不跟你上床
I mean hey if they don't trust you you're never gonna get them to sleep with you.
那是心理t生的最K目的
That should be the goal of any good therapist.
趁脆弱r下手  我的座右
Nail 'em while they're vulnerable. That's my motto.
很好  大家都醒了  g迎回
Oh good everyone's back. Welcome back everybody.
你好  尚恩
Hello Sean.
苈
Hey Gerry.
F在介B一大人物o各位
Um ladies and gentlemen we are in the presence of greatness.
苈逅{勃教授
Professor Gerald Lambeau.
M合W的菲德章得主
Field's medal winner for combinatorial mathematics.
l知道什N是菲德章?
Anyone know what the Field's medal is?
了不起  W界的Z
It's a really big deal. It's like the Nobel prize for math.
只是它四年才C一次
Except they only give it out once every four years.
很ゴ
It's a great thing.
是@人的s耀  好吧  下n
It's an amazing honor. Okay everybody that's it for today.
xx  Y拜一
Thanks. We'll see you Monday.
下次我佛洛伊德
We'll be talking about Freud.
他楹斡霉趴蔓|ⅠR  xx
Why he did enough cocaine to kill a small horse. Thank you.
- 你好?  - 真高d到你
- How are you?  - It's good to see you.
很高d到你
Good to see you.
我有一件你感d趣的事
Sean I think I got something interesting for ya.
致  需要血液和尿液?
What you have to have blood and urine? What's up?
同W你怎N不?
Why didn't you come to the reunion?
我在忙
You know I'm... I've been busy.
大家很想你
You were missed.
真的?
Really?
我多久]?
So how long has it been since we've seen each other?
南茜去世前
Before Nancy died.
是  很抱歉
Yeah I'm sorry.
我在巴黎_...  都是那死的h
I was in Paris. It was that damn conference.
我收到卡片  很好
I got your card. It was nice.
- ^  - 投球
- Come here.  - Now that's a takedown.
投得不e
Hey.
怎N?  博得同情]?
What happened? Did you get leniency or what?
@得保和一周纱蔚妮o
I got uh probation and then counseling two days a week.
你的伶牙利嘴真不是w的
Joke. You're a smoothie.
摩根!  快投球!
Come on Morgan! Just submit!
放_他  e^球的
Hey Bill just- just get off him. We're gonna miss the game.
我行程很M  我很忙
I've got a full schedule. I'm very busy.
@孩子不可思h  前所未
This- This boy is incredible. I've never seen anything like him.
是什N他@N不可思h?
What makes him so incredible Gerry?
^拉努?
You ever heard of Ramanujan?
^...]有
Yeah yeah. No.
他是男人
It's a man.
活在一百多年前  印度人
He lived over 100 years ago. He was Indian.
- 卓越成就  - 卓越成就
- Dots not feathers.  - Not feathers. Yeah.
他住在茅屋e  ]受^教育
He lived in this tiny hut somewhere in India. He had no formal education.
- o法取得任何科W著述  - 需要咖啡?
- He had no access to any scientific work.  - Coffee?
- 你呢  先生?  - 一c就好
- You sir?  - Just a little.
但他偶然lF一本fWn本
But he came across this old math book
sl明y倒W家已久的理
and from the simple text he was able to extrapolate theories that had baffled mathematicians for years.
Bm分  他是以...
Yes. Continued fractions. He wrote uh...
- 他寄o虻墓帝  -
- Well he mailed it to Hardy at Cambridge.  - Yeah Cambridge. Yeah.
哈帝即刻t解那是天才之作
And Hardy immediately recognized the brilliance of his work.
把他У接
And brought him over to England.
然後他合作多年
And then they worked together for years.
造出令人d^的W理
Creating some of the most exciting math theory ever done.
拉努的天才oc比
This- This Ramanujan...his- his genius was unparalleled Sean.
@孩子就像他一
Well this boy's just like that.
但他有c防R性
But he's...he's a bit defensive.
我需要有人突破他的心防
I need someone who can get through to him.
像是我
Like me?
就是你
Yeah like you.
槭颤N?
Why?
因槟有相同背景
Well because you have the same kind of background.
什N背景?
What background?
你碜酝一^
Well you're from the same neighborhood.
他是南^人?
He's from Southie?
是的
Yeah.
南^的天才少年
Boy genius from Southie.
你之前找^心理t生?
How many shrinks you go to before me?
五
Five.
我猜  拜瑞  亨利  ]找瑞克吧
Let me guess. Barry? Henry? Not Rick?
拜  跟他碰面  一L一次就好
Sean please just meet with him once a week.
拜?
Please?
@就像打牌  e牌底
It's a poker game with this kid. Don't let him know what you've got.
他或S已看^你的
He probably even read your book if he could find it.
他要找到很y
It's gonna be hard for him to find.
威
Hi Will.
@是尚恩圭  威杭汀
This is Sean Maguire. Will Hunting.
你好
How are ya?
好  _始
Yeah. Let's get started.
戆
Yeah let's do it.
_始治吧
I'm pumped. Let's let the healing begin.
出去
Will you excuse us?
麻┠
Yeah please Tom.
你也出去
You too Gerry.
好  然
Yeah of course.
你好?
How are you?
你是南^哪e人?
Where you from in Southie?
我喜g你@的b潢
I like what you've done with the place.
xx
Oh thanks.
@些都是零I的...
Do you buy all these books retail...
是派人I的整套心理?
or do you send away for like a "shrink kit" that comes with all these volumes included?
你喜g看?
Do you like books?
喜g
Yeah.
@些你x^?
Did you read any of these books?
不知道
I don't know.
那些呢
How about any of these books?
大概]有
Probably not.
幽切┠?  看^]?
What about the ones on the top shelf? You read those?
看^
Yeah I read those.
很好  你有什N感想?
Good for you. What do you think about 'em?
我不是他的碜鲎x蟾
I'm not here for a fuckin' book report.
那是你的  你怎N不x
They're your books. Why don't you read 'em?
我x^  非x不可
I did. I had to.
一定花了你不少rg
Must've taken you a long time.
是的
Yeah it did.
美通史  第一
United States of America: A Complete History Volume l.
天哪  想看真的v史的
Jesus. If you wanna read a real history book
x辛恩的
read Howard Zinn's A People's History in the United States.
那本你大吃一@
That book'll fuckin' knock you on your ass.
比姆斯基的更好?
Better than Chomsky's Manufacturing Consent?
你X得那是本好?
Do you think that's a good book?
我搞不懂你@些人  他的
You fuckin' people baffle me.
把X都花在@些可笑的上
You spend all your money on these fuckin' fancy books.
浪M在不Φ上面
You surround yourselves with 'em. They're the wrong fuckin' books.
什N是他的Φ?
What are the right fuckin' books Will?
^Q起淼
Whatever blows your hair back.
我剩的^不多
Yeah. Haven't got much hair left.
你槭颤N不把戒了
Hey you know you'd be better shoving that cigarette up your ass.
δ愕慕】涤泻锰
It'd probably be healthier for you.
我知道  抽妨K我瑜珈
Yeah I know. It really gets in the way of my yoga.
你\?
You work out huh?
你e重?
What you lift?
Yeah.
e重C?
Nautilus?
不  ♀
No free weights.
真的?
Oh really?
♀?
Free weights huh?
很行
Yeah. Yeah big time. Just like that.
你e多少?
What do you bench?
285  你呢?
285. What do you bench?
你的?
You paint that?
你?
Yeah. Do you paint?
你雕塑?
Do you sculpt?
不
No.
喜gg?
Do you like art?
不
No.
喜g音?
Do you like music?
真
This is a real piece of shit.
告V我你X得怎N
Oh tell me what you really think.
lY}s混y
Just the linear and impressionistic mix makes a very muddled composition.
P法H有印象派L
It's also a Winslow Homer rip- off except you got whitey rowin' the boat there.
那倒怪了  我K不想模仿莫内
Well it's art Monet. It wasn't very good.
我在意的不是那
That's not really what concerns me though.
你在意什N?
What concerns you?
色彩
Just the coloring.
你知道?
You know what the real bitch of it is?
@是以底之的
It's paint- by- number.
以底稚仙?  至少@色彩我著迷
Is it color- by- number? Because the colors are fascinating to me.
真的?  色彩怎?
Aren't they really?
我想你差c就要割耳朵了
You bet. I think you're about one step away from cuttin' your fuckin' ear off.
真的?
Really?
]e
Oh yeah.
那我搬到法改名梵Y
Think I should move to the south of France change my name to "Vincent".
^"暴L雨中的港口"?
You ever heard the sayin' "any port in a storm"?
^
Yeah.
也S指的就是你
Yeah maybe that means you.
哪方面?
In what way?
也S你正在暴L雨中
Maybe you're in the middle of a storm a big fuckin' storm.
也S吧
Yeah maybe.
天色昏暗  海浪撞粜〈
The sky's fallin' on your head. The waves are crashin' over your little boat.
就要嗔
The oars are about to snap.
你牧  迫切需要港口
You just piss in your pants. You're cryin' for the harbor.
@是你成樾睦磲t生的原因
So maybe you do what you gotta do to get out. You know maybe you became a psychologist.
答α  就是@
Bingo. That's it.
我做事吧  你妨K我了
Let me do my job now. You start with me. Come on.
也S你娶e女人
Maybe you married the wrong woman.
也S你v小心c
Maybe you should watch your mouth.
小心c  好?
Watch it right there chief all right?
]e  你娶e女人了
That's it isn't it? You married the wrong woman.
l生什N事?
What happened?
她你了?
What did she leave you?
她是不是搞上e的男人?
Was she you know...banging some other guy?
再ξ姨太oY就宰了你
If you ever disrespect my wife again I will end you.
我他的宰了你
I will fuckin' end you.
到]?
Got that chief?
rg到了
Time's up.
是的
Yeah.
稍息  晌
At ease gentlemen.
你]事吧?
You okay?
如果你不再想他  我t解
Look I'll understand if you don't wanna meet with him again.
星期四下午四c
Thursday 4:00.
一定要他
Make sure the kid's here.
好  xx
Yeah. Thanks.
你戴那副眼R好可
Well you look lovely in those glasses.
多x你
Thank you very much.
真漂亮
They're just beautiful.
我一直想擦{色眼影
Yes I always wanted dark blue eye shadow.
美O了
Wonderful.
我在英L大  念好W校
Growing up in England you know I went to a very nice school.
就是那NeO  有M...
You know it was kind of progressive organic...
又立自主的私立W校
do- it- yourself private school.
然後是很有X途的哈佛tW院
Then Harvard. Hopefully med school.
你知道我lF什N?
You know I figured out
最後我的X子  r值25f美金
by the end my brain's gonna be worth $250  000.
起砗芸膳掳
That sounded horrible didn't it?
再硪槐"~泰"
Bring me another mai tai!
酷  你父母一定很缝陡跺X
Yeah that's cool. I mean I bet your parents were happy to pay.
e  我自己付  我^承了za
No I was happy to pay. I inherited the money.
那NX都o哈佛?
Wow. Is Harvard gettin' all that money?
不  斯坦福  I後^去
No Stanford. I'm going there in June when I graduate.
所以你只是想利用@水手
All right so you just wanted to use this sailor and then run away huh?
我要先拿你做解剖
I was gonna you know experiment on you for anatomy class first obviously.
@拥脑  好吧
In that case that's fine.
想看我魔g?
Hey you wanna see my magic tricks Skylar?
好啊
Of course.
好  保C...
All right. Promise to...
好的
All right.
@是o你的  道夫
This one's for you Rudolph.
等等  你需要我的魔杖
Wait wait. You need my wand.
好  敲一下
All right give me a hit. Thank you. All right.
xx  @些焦糖消失
I'm gonna make all these caramels disappear.
浜昧?
You ready? Ready.
一 二 三
One two three.
全不了
They're all gone.
有兔子比^成功
That was my...It works better when I have my rabbit.
我不常s
I don't really date you know that much.
真可惜  我...
How very unfortunate... I think for me.
你懂我意思  我知道你在想什N
You know what I mean? I know you've been thinking about it.
- 我]有  - 我知道你有
- Oh no I haven't.  - Yes you have.
真的]有
No I really haven't.
你有  你想要睡前一吻
Yes you have. You were hoping to get a good night kiss.
不  我想要睡前一炮
No you know I tell ya I was hopin' to get a good night laid.
我意勉接受一吻
But I'll settle for like a kiss you know?
你很高尚
How very noble of you.
xx
Thank you.
不  我真的想要一吻
No I was...I was hopin' for a kiss.
何不F在就解Q?
Well why don't we just get it out of the way now?
F在?
Right now?
Yeah. Come on.
我吃到你的酸S瓜了
I think I got some of your pickle.
又是你?
You again huh?
跟我
Come with me.
F在要致?
So what's this?
@是男人的行家x?
A Taster's Choice moment between guys?
@e真不e
This is really nice.
你喜g天Z?  @算傥锺?
You got a thing for swans? Is this like a fetish?
@是需要花crg的事?
Is it something like maybe we need to devote some time to?
我在想你批u我的事
Thought about what you said to me the other day. About my painting.
失眠大半夜的思索後
Stayed up half the night thinking about it.
突然我想到一件事
Something occurred to me.
接著就沉沉入睡
I fell into a deep peaceful sleep and haven't thought about you since.
你知道我r想到什N?
You know what occurred to me?
不知道
No.
你只是孩子
You're just a kid.
你根本不缘媚阍谡f什N
You don't have the faintest idea what you're talking about.
xx  槭颤N?
Why thank you.
]PS
It's all right.
因你]x_^波士D
You've never been out of Boston.
是]有
Nope.
所以你g  你可能...
So if I asked you about art you'd probably give me the skinny...
提出g籍中的粗\{
on every art book ever written.
有P米_朗基_  你知道很多
Michelangelo? You know a lot about him.
他的政治抱  他和教皇...
Life's work political aspirations. Him and the pope...
性A向  所有作品  ?
Sexual orientation. The whole works right?
但你不知道西斯汀教堂的馕
I bet you can't tell me what it smells like in the Sistine Chapel.
你]站在那河^p美的天花板
You never actually stood there and looked up at that beautiful ceiling.
我看^
Seeing that.
如果我P於女人的事
If I ask you about women.
你八成f出人偏好的
you'll probably give me a syllabus of your personal favorites.
你可能上^状未
You may have even been laid a few times.
但你f不出在女人身旁醒...
But you can't tell me what it feels like to wake up next to a woman...
那N幸福的滋味
and feel truly happy.
你是很倔的孩子
You're a tough kid.
你f莎士比的
I ask you about war you'd probably throw Shakespeare at me right?
"共赴  H鄣呐笥"
"Once more into the breach dear friends."
但你]接近^
But you've never been near one.
]把好友的^抱在膝w上...
You've never held your best friend's head in your lap...
看著他吐出最後一口
and watch him gasp his last breath lookin' to you for help.
矍  你引述十四行
If I asked you about love you'd probably quote me a sonnet.
但你]看^女人的脆弱
But you've never looked at a woman and been totally vulnerable.
她能以p眼舻鼓
Known someone that could level you with her eyes.
感X上帝天使槟阆路
Feelin' like God put an angel on Earth just for you.
她能牡鬲z⒛阏救出
Who could rescue you from the depths of hell.
你不t解成樗天使的滋味
And you wouldn't know what it's like to be her angel.
碛λ的壑钡接肋h
To have that love for her be there forever.
v@一切  v癌症
Through anything. Through cancer.
你o法w在t院睡整整月  握著她的手
And you wouldn't know about sleepin' sittin' up in a hospital room for two months holding her hand.
因獒t生看到你的眼神就明白...
because the doctors could see in your eyes...
客rg的定δo效
that the terms "visiting hours" don't apply to you.
你不t解真正的失去
You don't know about real loss
唯有e人凫蹲约翰拍荏w
'cause that only occurs when you love something more than you love yourself.
我岩赡愀夷廴
I doubt you've ever dared to love anybody that much.
看著你  我]看到明自信
I look at you. I don't see an intelligent confident man.
我看到被傻的狂妄孩子
I see a cocky scared shitless kid.
但你是天才  ]人能否J
But you're a genius Will. No one denies that.
]人能t解你的深度
No one could possibly understand the depths of you.
但你看我的就J定t解我
But you presume to know everything about me because you saw a painting of mine.
你把我的人生撕裂了
You ripped my fuckin' life apart.
你是孤  Π?
You're an orphan right?
你想我X得你日子有多苦...
Do you think I'd know the first thing about how hard your life has been...
你的感受  你是l...
how you feel who you are...
只是因槲铱催^孤rI?
because I read Oliver Twist?
太p易J定你了?
Does that encapsulate you?
我不在乎  因...
Personally I don't give a shit about all that because...
你知道?  我不能靠任何籍JR你
You know what? I can't learn anything from you...I can't read in some fuckin' book.
除非你想自己  你是l
Unless you wanna talk about you who you are.
那我就有d趣了  我意加入
And I'm fascinated. I'm in.
但你不想那N做  ?
But you don't wanna do that do you sport?
你怕你被f出淼脑到
You're terrified of what you might say.
到你f了  大哥
Your move chief.
喂?
Hello? Hello?
Hello?
瓦m帝教授  又是你?
Professor Valenti are you calling me again?
怪胎
Freak.
天哪  你打ol?
Christ who did you call?
]有  我忘了a
No one. I forgot the number.
你他智障?
You fuckin' retarded?
冒雨打  竟忘了a
You went all the way out there in the rain and you didn't bring the number.
那是你的免M
No it was your mother's 900 number. I just ran out of quarters.
e扯上我  我上^你
Why don't we get off on mothers? I just got off yours.
很好笑  摩根  太炫了
That's pretty funny Morgan. That's a fuckin' nickel bitch.
- ^m跟我作看看  - 好了
- Keep antagonizing me. Watch what happens.- All right then Morgan.
- 等著瞧  - 好了  摩根
- Watch what happens.- All right then Morgan.
再整我啊
Keep fuckin' with me.
不准抽
No smoking.
什N叫]v?  一^
What do you mean he didn't talk? You were in there for an hour.
他就坐著等Y束
He just sat there counting the seconds until the session was over.
人印象U深刻的
Pretty impressive actually.
他槭颤N要那N做?
Why would he do that?
C明他不想v就不必v
To prove to me he doesn't have to talk to me if he doesn't want to.
@是小孩玩的瞪人比?
What is this? Some kind of staring contest between two kids from the old neighborhood?
而且我不能先v
Yeah it is and I can't talk first.
我知道你的理  v山大
We know your theory Alexander.
但@孩子找出蔚缀D
But the boy's found a simple geometrical picture.
罱Y行不通
A tree structure won't work.
他把cB起砹
Look now. He's joining the two vertices.
但我算出
But I can do the sum.
那是集合的方法
It's how you group the terms Alexander.
但是如果@幼...
But Gerry. If we do the whole thing this way then...
看@e
Hey look look.
我下砹  @颖容^
I wrote it down. It's simpler this way.
有些人就是走\
Sometimes people get lucky.
你是很明的人
You're a brilliant man.
我有一次搭wC  坐在C上...
You know I was on this plane once and I'm sittin' there and...
CLV播完w行于三f五千尺
the captain gets on he does his whole you know "we'll be cruisin' at 35000 feet  "
他放下克L後忘了P掉
But then he puts the mike down. He forgets to turn it off.
他D向副{f...
So he turns to the copilot. He's like...
我F在很想要口交和咖啡
"You know all I could use right now is a fuckin' blow job and a cup of coffee."
空服T_去跟他f克L]P
So the stewardess fuckin' goes bombin' up from the back of the plane to tell him the microphone's still on.
C尾有人f"e忘了上咖啡"
This guy in the back of the plane's like "Hey hon don't forget the coffee."
你搭^wC?
You ever been on a plane?
]有  那只是笑
No but it's a fuckin' joke.
用第一人Q比^好笑
It works better if I tell it in the first person.
]e
Yeah it does.
我做^
I have been laid you know?
真的?  很好
Really? Good for you.
我很害
Big time big time.
很害?
Big time huh?
我上Y拜有s
I went on a date last week.
怎N?
How'd it go?
很好
It was good.
要再s?
Goin' out again?
不知道
I don't know.
槭颤N?
Why not?
我]打o她
Haven't called her.
天哪  你真]用
Christ you're an amateur.
- 我知道我在致  - 真的?
- I know what I'm doin'.  - Really?
放心  我知道我在致
Yeah. Don't worry about me. I know what I'm doin'.
@女孩很漂亮  明L趣
Yeah but this girl was like you know beautiful. She's smart. She's fun.
她跟我以前JR的女生不一
She's different from most of the girls I've been with.
那就打o她  _密W
So call her up Romeo.
自己lF她]那N明?
Why so I can realize she's not that smart.
lF她其很o聊?
That she's fuckin' boring? You know I mean you don't...
@女孩F在很完美
This girl's like fuckin' perfect right now.
我不想破
I don't wanna ruin that.
或S是你不想破哪阕约旱耐昝
Maybe you're perfect right now. Maybe you don't wanna ruin that.
我X得那是O好的哲W
But I think that's a super philosophy Will.
@涌梢砸惠子不JR任何人
That way you can go through your entire life without ever having to really know anybody.
我太太一o就放屁
My wife used to fart when she was nervous.
她有各N奇妙的小特|
She had all sorts of wonderful idiosyncrasies.
你知道  她睡X放屁
You know she used to fart in her sleep.
抱歉跟你v@N事
Just thought I'd share that with you.
有天晚上大到把狗吵醒
One night it was so loud it woke the dog up.
她醒碚f  是你  我f是
She woke up and gone like "Was that you?" I said "Yeah."
我不忍心告V她  天哪
I didn't have the heart to tell her. Oh God.
她把自己臭醒?
She woke herself up?
是的
Yes.
天哪  她去世赡炅
Oh Christ. But Will she's been dead two years
而那是我得的事
And that's the shit I remember.
像那拥男∈潞芷婷
It's wonderful stuff you know? Little things like that.
那是我最想念的事
Yeah but those are the things I miss the most.
@些小特|她成槲姨太
Those little idiosyncrasies that only I knew about. That's what made her my wife.
她也知道我所有的小瑕疵
Boy and she had the goods on me too. She knew all my little peccadillos.
人Q之椴煌昝
People call these things "imperfections".
其不然  那才是好|西
But they're not. That's the good stuff.
能x褡lM入我的世界
And then we get to choose who we let into our weird little worlds.
你K不完美
You're not perfect sport.
我不吊你胃口
And let me save you the suspense.
你JR的女生也不完美
This girl you met she isn't perfect either.
}是你是否完美地合m
But the question is whether or not you're perfect for each other.
H密PS就是@N回事
That's the whole deal. That's what intimacy is all about.
你可以知道全世界的事
Now you can know everything in the world sport.
但l掘的方法就是去L
but the only way you're findin' out that one is by givin' it a shot.
你不能跟我@糟老^W
You certainly won't learn from an old fucker like me.
就算我知道我也不告V你
Even if I did know I wouldn't tell a pissant like you.
槭颤N?
Yeah why not?
你其他事都告V我了  天哪
You told me every other fuckin' thing. Jesus Christ.
你的比任何心理t生都多
Fuckin' talk more than any shrink I ever seen in my life.
我只是教心理W  我f^我不是心理t生
I teach the shit. I didn't say I knew how to do it.
那N  你想^再婚?
You ever think about gettin' remarried?
我太太死了
My wife's dead.
所以才叫"再婚"
Hence the word "remarried."
她死了
She's dead.
我想那是O好的哲W
Yeah well I think that's a super philosophy Sean.
@涌梢砸惠子不JR任何人
I mean that way you can actually go through the rest of your life without ever really knowing anybody.
rg到了
Time's up.
eP
Hold it open.
xx
Thanks.
你去哪e了?
Where have you been?
Σ黄  我...我很忙
I'm sorry. I've been like...I've been really busy and...
我也是
Mmm. Me too.
我以槟打
Yeah. I...I thought you'd call.
我是f
I mean.
- 我相愉快  - 的_如此
- We had a really good time.  - I had a really good time too.
Σ黄鹞腋阍伊
I mean I just...I...I'm sorry you know. I blew it.
不  ]PS
No. No I mean you know it's all right.
你不再我一遍
Yeah um so I was wonderin' if uh if you know you'd give me another crack at it.
我再s你出去
You know let me take you out again.
不行
I can't.
好吧
All right.
不  我不是永h不行
Oh no I didn't...I didn't mean I can't like ever.
F在不行
I just can't right now.
我得做|子光V分配
I've got to assign the proton spectrum for "ebogamine".
起碛腥  其很o聊
All that sounds really really interesting. It's actually fantastically boring.
- 好吧  - 或S改天吧
- All right um...  - Maybe some other time.
那明天呢?
Like tomorrow?
好啊
Um yeah all right.
- 好的  - 好的
- Okay.  - Okay.
- 再  - 再
- Bye.  - Bye.
你在@致?
What are you doing here?
我等不到明天了
I couldn't wait till tomorrow.
你哪号到@?
Where the fuck did you get this?
我得跟你同W上床
I had to sleep with someone in your class.
希望是穿拖鞋又有口臭的人
Oh I hope it was someone with the open- toed sandals and the really bad breath.
走  去找纷
Come on. Let's go have some fun.
不行  我得念@
No I've got to learn this.
你不明天就要_刀吧
Well you're not going into surgery tomorrow are you?
不是
No.
走吧
Let's go.
我的天  我的狗A了
Oh my God! My dog is winning!
加油  迷F!  快跑!
Come on Misty! Come on! Run! Look at that! Come on!
他在那  迷FI先!
Look there he goes. Misty run! Come on!
我A了
We won.
它大@全
He totally won.
你在@L大的?
So did you grow up around here then?
不h  南波士D
Not far. South Boston.
A了比我好
Still glowing from my win.
看你烦蛇@
Look at you. You're so happy.
我的幼舆好吧
And what was that like then?
很正常  ]什N特e
It was normal I guess. Nothin' special.
你有很多兄弟姊妹?
Do you got lots of brothers and sisters?
- 我有很多兄弟姊妹?  - 我在你呢
- Do I have a lot of brothers and sisters?  - That's what I said.
我是天主教徒  你f呢?
Well Irish Catholic what do you think?
?
Right. That's right. How many?
告V你你也不信
You wouldn't believe me if I told you.
槭颤N?  f啊  五?
Why? Go on. What? Five?
七?  八?  ?
Seven? Eight? How many?
我有十二哥哥
I have 12 big brothers.
你才]有!
You do not!
我l誓  我是幸\十三
No I swear to God. I swear to God. I'm lucky 13 right here.
你知道他的名字?
Do you know all their names?
然知道  他是我哥哥
Do I...Yeah they're my brothers.
叫什N名字?
What are they called?
R奇  瑞奇  丹尼  泰瑞...
Marky Ricky Danny Terry...
奇  大l  提米  米...
Mikey Davey Timmy Tommy...
桃  _比  尼和布R恩
Joey Robby Johnny and Brian.
再f一遍
Say it again.
R奇  瑞奇  丹尼  泰瑞...
Marky Ricky Danny Terry...
奇  大l  提米  米...
Mikey Davey Timmy Tommy...
桃  _比  尼和布R恩
Joey Robby Johnny and Brian.
有小威
And Willy.
小威?
Willy?
威
Will.
你常和他面?
Do you still see all of them?
他都住南^
Yeah well they all live in Southie.
我跟其中三住
I'm livin' with three of 'em right now.
是?
Oh yeah?
我好想他
I'd like to meet them.
好  就去他
Yeah we'll do that.
我昨晚x^你的
Oh you know I read your book last night.
原硎悄
Oh so you're the one.
你o退伍人?
Do you still uh...Do you still counsel veterans?
]有
No I don't.
槭颤N?
Why not?
我太太生病r就]做了
Well I gave it up when my wife got sick.
你有]有想^若]遇你太太
You ever wonder what your life would be like if you
你的生活怎?
uh if you never met your wife?
]有她不比^好?
What? Wonder if I'd be better off without her?
不  我]f比^好
No no no I'm not saying like better off.
我]那意思
I didn't mean it like that.
]PS  很重要的}
It's all right. It's an important question.
是有不好的r候...
'Cause you'll have bad times...
但那是你X悟到好的事
But that'll always wake you up to the good stuff you weren't paying attention to.
你不後悔JR你太太?
And you don't regret meetin' your wife?
因槲椰F在的痛苦?
Why? 'Cause the pain I feel now?
是有z憾
Oh I got regrets Will.
但我不後悔跟她共度的每一天
But I don't regret a single day I spent with her.
你r知道她是理想ο?
So when did you know like that she was the one for you?
1975年10月21日
October 21 1975.
天哪  你他的得日期?
Jesus Christ. You know the fuckin' day?
那是世界大第六
Oh yeah 'cause it was game six of the World Series.
tm史上最重大的球
Biggest game in Red Sox history.
]e
Yeah sure.
我和朋友睡人行道排I票
My friends and I had slept out all night to get tickets.
你有票?
You got tickets?
比天...
Yep. Day of the game...
我坐在酒吧等球_始...
I was sittin' in a bar waitin' for the game to start...
有女孩走M...
and in walks this girl...
那是龊馨舻那蛸
It was an amazing game though.
八局下半
You know bottom of the eighth Carbo ties it up.
六比六平手
It was 6- 6.
打到第十二局  下半r
It went to 12. Bottom of the 12th.
矮冬瓜菲克斯上
in stepped Carlton Fisk old Pudge.
他站上本  姿莺芄
Steps up to the plate. You know he's got that weird stance.
打舫鋈!
And then...Boom! He clocks it you know.
左外野高w球!
High fly ball down the left field line!
三f五千人站起η蚝
Thirty- five thousand people on their feet yellin' at the ball.
菲斯克像l了似地]手f
But that's nothin' 'cause Fisk he's wavin' at the ball like a madman.
"w^去!  w^去!  w^去!"
"Get over! Get over! Get over!"
然後球w到界
Then it hits the foul pole. He goes ape- shit.
三f五千名球迷_到錾
And 35  000 fans...They charge the field you know.
他大叫"大家_  _..."
Yeah and he's fuckin' blowin' people outta the way. "Get outta the way! Get outta the way!"
我真不敢相信你有票!
I can't fuckin' believe you had tickets to that fuckin' game!
你有_到錾?
Did you rush the field?
我]_到錾  我不在
No I didn't rush the fuckin' field. I wasn't there.
什N?
What?
我跟我未淼睦掀旁诤染
No I was in a bar havin' a drink with my future wife.
你e^菲斯克的全敬?
You missed Pudge Fisk's home run.
Right.
跟一不JR的女人喝酒?
to have a fuckin' drink with some lady you never met?
你看看她  令人@W
Yeah but you should have seen her. She was a stunner.
我才不管他的...
I don't care if...
她整屋子亮起
Oh no no she lit up the room.
- 哪怕是走M淼氖呛我也不在乎  - 你了!
- I don't care if Helen of Troy walks into the room.  - Oh Helen of Troy!
天哪  那你朋友呢
That's game six! Oh my God and who were these friends of yours?
- 就@N放^你?  - 他]k法
- They let you get away with that?  - They had to.
你跟他怎Nf?
What did you say to 'em?
我把票滑^去f
I just slid my ticket across the table.
抱歉  我要去找一女孩
I said "Sorry guys. I gotta see about a girl."
- 我要去找一女孩?  - !
- "I gotta go see about a girl"?  - Yes!
你那Nf?
That's what you said?
他就放^你了?
They let you get away with that?
他看到我J真的眼睛
Oh yeah. They saw it in my eyes that I meant it.
你耍我吧
You're kiddin' me?
我]耍你
No I'm not kidding you Will.
所以我F在不因...
That's why I'm not talkin' right now about some girl I saw at a bar 20 years ago...
年]和她f而懊悔K生
and how I always regretted not goin' over and talkin' to her.
我不後悔跟南茜Y的18年
I don't regret the 18 years I was married to Nancy.
不後悔樗的病放o
I don't regret the six years I had to give up counseling when she got sick.
不後悔那最後啄晔刂重病的她
And I don't regret the last years when she got really sick.
更不後悔e^球
And I sure as hell don't regret missin' a damn game.
只是有cz憾
That's regret.
看到那銮蛸是不e的
Would have been nice to catch that game though.
我不缘冒冬瓜t不
I didn't know Pudge was gonna hit a home run.
我在球錾虾苡杏  我很高
You know I'm very very useful on the court. I'm extremely tall.
你]那N高
You're not that tall.
我灌@
I dunk.
我能打NBA?
Will I ever play in the N.B.A.?
^可以
"It is decidedly so." Hmph.
槭颤N老是待在@?
Why do we always stay here?
因楸任壹液
'Cause it's nicer than my place.
但我]去^你家
Yes but I've never seen your place.
我知道
I know.
我什Nr候能到你朋友和哥哥?
When am I gonna meet your friends and your brothers?
他不常磉@e
Well they don't really come down here that much.
我可以到南波士D
I think I can make it to South Boston.
有ch
It's kind of a hike.
是我是他不得人?
Is it me you're hiding from them or the other way around?
好  我去
All right we'll go.
r?
When?
不知道  下Y拜吧
I don't know. We'll go sometime next week.
如不我他就再也不跟你上床
What if I said I would not sleep with you again until you let me meet your friends?
清晨四c半  他醒了
I'd say it's like 4:30 in the mornin'. They're probably up.
天哪  男人真ou
Oh my God. Men are shameless.
你男人就只用小弟弟思考
If you're not thinking with your wiener then you're acting directly on its behalf.
H代表我的小弟弟向你A支
You bet. And on behalf of my wiener can I get an advance payment?
不知道  我
I don't know. Let's ask.
前途o量
"Outlook does not look good."
- 什N?  -
- What?  - Fuck the...
查克  ]事  ^m睡
Hey Chuck. No. Nothing. Go back to sleep.
你去打NBA才前途o量
"Outlook"? That's the same thing that told you you was gonna play in the N.B.A.
]e  所以你最好_始I季票
Exactly so look out. You'd better start buying some season tickets.
我很高  我喜g穿短
Mmm! I plan to. I'm tall. I like wearing shorts.
勾射  灌@
Hook hook. Dunk dunk.
你]那N高
You're not that tall.
我有  我三分射@很行
Yes I am. Maybe I'm all about three points.
我就很打"全敬"
I'm all about home runs.
e用\有gZ影射
Stop mixing your sporting metaphors.
妖精的老二在猴子屁眼e
A leprechaun's got his dick in the monkey's ass.
摩根跑出碚f  我不介意  我不介意
Morgan comes runnin' in goin' "l don't mind it. I don't mind..."
你竟挑我醉r她
Well I can't believe you brought Skylar here when we're fuckin' all bombed and drinkin'.
我很y得一起喝酒
I know Morgan. It's a real rarity we'd be all drinkin'.
我叔叔R帝只要一喝酒  就狂g一年半d
My uncle Marty drinks. He'll go on a bender for six eight months.
我v^他被r下淼氖]?
Did I ever tell ya what happened to him when he was drivin' up there and got pulled over?
我跟你v
I told you guys right? Let me tell ya what happened to my uncle Marty.
你知道
Because you oughta know this.
到@老是他v故事
He's always tellin' stories. Every time we come here he's got another story.
@我早就^了
But we all heard this one.
是f吧  快v
Go ahead. Say it anyway.
我v  多x  Q我l言
I will go ahead. Thanks a lot. Guess I have the floor now.
我叔叔_回家
My uncle Marty's drivin' home right?
撞到渖
Bombed out of his tree right?
他醉得一塌糊T
Just hammered out of his gourd. Just wrecked.
州警把他r下  我叔叔K了
This state trooper sees him pulls him over. So my uncle's fucked basically.
州警要他下走直
Got him out of the car tryin' to make him walk the line.
Y果他吐在州警身上...
He gets out of the car pukes...
州警_信他超^酒精舛
and the statie's pretty sure he's over the legal limit.
正要把他戴上手D送去坐牢
So he's about to throw the cuffs on him and put him in jail.
突然五十a外一他的巨
All of a sudden 50 yards down the road there's this huge fuckin' boom.
州警一大跳  D身
Statie gets real spooked. He turns around.
?
He got shot?
不  是...
No. So...So...
你^@故事了
You heard this story before.
得了  摩根
Yeah Morgan stop. Stop.
是e人的撞到  出事了
Some other guy's car had hit a tree. There was an accident.
之...
Anyway...
]嘴!
Shut the fuck up!
我要扭嗄悴弊
I'm gonna break your neck.
]嘴
Shut up!
他跟你f^@故事了
He told you the story once before.
州警跟我叔叔f"e走"
So he tells my uncle "Stay here. Don't move."
就跑去理另一起事故
Statie goes runnin' down the road to deal with the other accident.
躺在尿和I吐物中追昼後...
After a few minutes of just lyin' in his own piss and vomit...
我叔叔才想到  他在那致
my uncle starts wonderin' what he's doin' there.
於是站起黹_回家
Gets up gets in his car and just drives home.
隔天早上我叔叔昏迷不醒
The next mornin' my uncle's just passed out.
他到敲T
He hears this knockin' at the door.
下抢_Tf"什N事"
So he goes downstairs pulls the door open "What?"
是r下他的州警
It's the state trooper that pulled him over.
州警f"我操  什N事?  你明知故"
Statie says "Fuck you mean 'What?' You know what."
"我昨晚r下你  你逃走了"
"I pulled you over last night is what and you took off."
叔叔f"我@子]^你"
He's like "l never seen you before in my life.
"我整晚在家  你yv什N"
I've been home all night with my kids. I don't know who the fuck you are."
州警f"eb蒜了  到"
He's like "You know who I am. Let me get in your garage."
我叔叔f"什N?"
My uncle's like "What?" He said
州警f"我去你的"
"You heard me. Let me get in your garage."
我叔叔他到齑蜷_T
He was like "All right. Fine." Takes him out to the garage opens the door.
警就在我叔叔的煅e
And there's...The statie's police cruiser is in my uncle's garage.
他醉到他的_e回家了
He was so fuckin'...He was so fuckin' hammered he drove the wrong car home.
最诺氖侵菥好糗...
The best part about it is the fuckin' state trooper...
他整晚什N都]做
was so embarrassed he didn't do anything.
_著我叔叔的挨家挨粽胰
He'd been drivin' around all night in my uncle's Chevelle lookin' for the house.
你的故事重c是什N?
All right Chuck what the fuck is the point of your story?
他逃跑了就是重c
He got away. That's the point.
- 好  }是...  - 你是不是...
- Well question...  - Come on.
少砹
Stop.
- 你想弄清楚又不好意思  - 好了  你e糗人家了
- I'm tryin' to clarify somethin'.  - You're embarrassing him.
- 因槟阒v的故事]什N意x  - ]什N意x
- It doesn't make any sense.  - It does make sense.
故事e|西的
if you listen to the story and quit askin' questions.
摩根  看@故事你懂不懂
Well let's see if you can get this one. I've got a little story for you.
好  一老夫妻在床上
All right there's an old couple in bed.
和派帝
Mary and Paddie.
Y婚50周年那天他醒
They wake up on the morning of their 50th anniversary.
深情地望著派帝f
Mary looks over and gazes adoringly at Paddie.
天哪  你真是一大哥  我勰
She's like "Oh Jesus Paddie. You're such a good- looking feller. I love ya.
我要送你一件Y物
I want to give ya a little present.
你渴望什N我都o你
Anything your little heart desires I'm goin' to give it to ya.
你想要什N?
What would ya like?
派帝f@真是甜蜜的提h
Paddie's like "Oh gee Mary. That's a very sweet offer.
五十年砭蜕僖|西
Now in 50 years there's one thing that's been missing.
我希望你臀掖道叭  我想要
and uh I would like you to give me a blow job. I would like for it."
f好
Mary's like "All right."
她把假牙拿掉...
She takes her teeth out...
放M杯子e  然後退吹
puts 'em in the glass. She gives him a blow job.
之後派帝f  @就是我最渴望
Afterwards Paddie's like "Yeah geez now that's what I've been missin'.
最勾魂z魄的事  他f
That was the most beautiful earth- shattering thing ever!
太棒了    我勰
Beautiful Mary! I love ya!
我能槟阕鍪颤N?
Is there anything that I can do for you?"
抬^看他f  "H一下"
Mary looks up to him and she goes "Give us a kiss."
我的天
Oh my God!
好
That's filthy.
不  我^更f心的
It's not that filthy. I've heard filthy.
L_  操!
Get off of me!
好  再
All right. See you guys later.
保重  比利
All right. Take it easy Bill.
xx你改我哈佛人的看法
So Skylar thanks for comin' by. Changed my opinion of Harvard people.
e急著下嗾Z  他跟我不同
You don't want to rush to judgment on that one 'cause they're not all like me.
我相信  很高dJR你
Oh. I'm sure. It was nice to meet ya.
小心
Take it easy. Slowly back away.
慢慢_
Oh come on. Brother.
你在致?  你要送我
I don't know what you're doin' dude. You're givin' us a ride.
你以槲以致?
What the fuck do I look like to you?
你要走路  o威
You're walkin' bitch. Will's takin' the car.
好  x了  很感激
All right thanks sucker. I appreciate it.
致镞@N正
I don't know what you're gettin' all serious about.
你是要先送我回家
You're droppin' me off first.
@雍懿豁路
It's really out of the way.
e以榻裢砜梢酝馑...
Oh okay. Just 'cause you don't have to sleep in your one- room palace tonight...
就懦蛇@
don't start thinkin' you're bad.
等一下  你f要去看你家
Hey wait a minute. You said we were gonna see your place.
今晚不行
Not tonight.
今晚不行  哪一晚都不行
Oh no not tonight. Not any other night.
他知道你一看^就甩了他
He knows once you see that shit- hole he's gettin' dropped like a bad habit.
但我想你哥哥
But I wanted to meet your brothers.
不  改天吧
We're gonna do that another time.
好吧
All right.
我需要匙
Need them keys.
空服T到就往走道上_
The stewardess hears this and goes haulin' ass down the aisle.
我f"e忘了咖啡"
I yell "Don't forget the coffee."
狗屁!  你]那Nf
No shit! You didn't say that.
拜  那是笑嘛
For Christ's sake Marty it's a joke.
我JR真的碰到@事的人
I know someone that actually happened to Marty.
只是笑
A joke.
苈
Gerry.
@很y找?
Have trouble findin' the place?
不  我搭程
No I took a cab.
提米  @是苈  大W同W
Timmy this is Gerry. We went to college together.
你好  幸
How you doin'? Nice to meet ya.
幸
Pleased to meet you.
你喝杯啤酒吧
Can I get you a beer?
不  沛G雅
Um no just a Perrier.
那是法文的K打水
That's French for club soda.
K打水  好
Club soda yeah.
有三明治
Couple of sandwiches too.
好
Sure.
算在我ど
Put it on my tab.
你打算要?
You ever plannin' on payin' your tab?
要  我@有中彩券
Yeah chief got the winning lottery ticket right here.
金多少?
What's the jackpot?
一千砂偃f
Twelve million.
我看不蚋
I don't think that'll cover it.
蚋赌愕淖性手g了
It'll cover your sex change operation.
怨?
Nuts?
不  xx
No thank you.
你想威
So you wanted to talk about Will.
好像很利
Well it seems to be going well.
我想是的
I think so.
你跟他^未]?
Have you talked to him at all about his future?
]到  在往事中打D
No we haven't gotten into that yet. We're still bangin' away at the past.
_始了
Maybe you should.
S多工作都急著找他
My phone's been ringing off the hook with job offers.
哪N工作?
What kind?
尖端科技W  智囊F
Cutting edge mathematics think tanks.
威的^X能l]的地方
The kind of place where a mind like Will's is given free rein.
那真好  但他]浜
That's great that there are offers but I don't really think he's ready for that.
我想你不明白
I'm not sure you understand Sean.
我不明白什N?
What don't I understand?
砹
Here you go guys.
xx你
Thanks Tim.
@邮种覆QQ的
Just so you don't get sticky fingers.
提米  能忙?
Tim can you help us?
我要一A
We're tryin' to settle a bet.
^s拿斯索克?
Ever heard of Jonas Salk?
被治K的小郝楸灾⒒颊
Sure. Cured polio.
^垡蛩固?
Ever heard of Albert Einstein?
苈逅{勃呢?  ^?
How about Gerald Lambeau? Ever heard of him?
]有
No.
xx
Thank you Tim.
lA了
So who won the bet?
我A了
I did.
@不是我的事
This isn't about me Sean.
我跟@年p人比不算什N
I'm nothing compared to this young man.
你^苈逅{勃?
You ever hear of Gerald Lambeau?
在1905年有S多以研究宇宙名的教授
In 1905 there were hundreds of professors renown for their study of the universe.
但改世界的s是...
But it was a 26- year- old Swiss patent clerk...
趁f暇r研究物理的26qk事T
doing physics in his spare time who changed the world.
你可以想像如果垡蛩固...
Can you imagine if Einstein would have given that up...
每天都喝得醉的怎?
just to get drunk with his buddies in Vienna every night.
我都失去一些|西
We all would have lost something.
而提米^不^他
Tim would never have heard of him.
非常』
Pretty dramatic Gerry.
不是
No it isn't Sean.
@孩子有天x
This boy has that gift.
他只是]方向  我o他
He just doesn't got the direction but we can give that to him.
在60年代曾有一...
Hey Gerry in the 1960s...
密西根大WI的年p人
there was a young man graduated from University of Michigan.
他的W很出色
Did some brilliant work in mathematics.
特e是有界集函
Specifically bounded harmonic functions.
他到柏克R助教  力@人
Then he went on to Berkeley. He was assistant professor. Showed amazing potential.
然後在蒙大拿州A得
Then he moved to Montana and he blew the competition away.
好  他是l?
Yeah so who was he?
泰德卡辛斯基
Ted Kaczynski.
]^
Haven't heard of him.
提米
Hey Timmy!
l是泰德卡辛斯基?
Who's Ted Kaczynski?
]包炸狂
Unabomber.
那就是我f的  他需要方向
That's exactly what I'm talking about. We gotta give this kid direction.
他能I世人  我能退
He can contribute to the world and we can help him do that.
方向是一回事  操v是另一回事
Direction's one thing. Manipulation's another.
你要他自己l掘
We have to let him find.
尚恩  我不是每晚坐在家e...
I'm not sitting at home every night...
策怎N摧他的人生!
twisting my mustache and hatching a plan to ruin this boy's life!
我18q就做高等W...
I was doing advanced mathematics when I was 18...
20年後才得到菲德章
and it still took me over 20 years to do something worthy of a Field's medal.
也S他不想照你的想法去做
Maybe he doesn't want what you want.
人生不只是一他的章
There's more to life than a fuckin' Field's medal.
@太重要了  要超越人立
This is too important Sean and it's above personal rivalry.
等等  我的是@孩子
Wait a minute. Let's talk about the boy.
楹尾唤o他rg想清楚要什N?
Why don't we give him time to figure out what he wants?
很棒的理  可槟造奇E
That's a wonderful theory Sean. It worked wonders for you didn't it?
你@自的混蛋!
Yeah it did you arrogant fuckin' prick!
我很z憾
Oh I'm sorry.
很z憾我砹  我是出於好意
I'm sorry that I came here today. I came here out of courtesy.
我想你⑴c@件事
I wanted to keep you in the loop.
我很高d能⑴c
Nice to be in the loop.
他此刻正在我安排的面中
The boy's in a meeting right now I set up for him over at McNeil.
威  我不清楚你的意思
Well Will I'm not exactly sure what you mean.
我已o你位了
We've already offered you a position.
@年^做事]人不拿酬金的
Nobody in this town works without a retainer guys.
你J檎业玫  我祝福你
You think you can find somebody who does you have my blessin'.
但]有人可以像我做得那N好
But I think we all know that person is not gonna represent you as well as I can.
我已o你年薪八f四加福利
Will our offer is $84  000 a year.
酬金
Retainer! Retainer.
你是要我F在o你F金?
You want us to give you cash right now?
慢c  我]那Nf
Whoa- ho- ho. Easy...Now I didn't say that.
但我口袋e如果有砂K
Allegedly your situation for you.
你的境同r@得改善
Would be concurrently improved if I had...$200 in my back pocket right now.
我]有  瑞
I don't think I can...Larry?
我有73K
I've got $73.
你收支票?
Will you take a check?
你@Ne止相可疑
Let me tell you somethin'. You're suspect.
你
Yeah you.
我不知道你的u怎
I don't know what your reputation is in this town
但耍@N花招  我一定{查
but after the shit you tried to pull today you can bet I'll be lookin' into you.
P於我未淼暮献
Now any business we have heretofore
和我的律
you can speak with my aforementioned attorney.
再  在那天到砬
Good day gentlemen.
拼命只畎
And until that day comes keep your ear to the grindstone.
怎N?
How's it goin'?
很好
Fine.
好
Good.
要兔?
Want some help?
不要!
No!
o我看一下  我要去球
Come on. Give me one little peek and we'll go to the batting cages.
我一定要念@
No. It is actually important that I learn this.
真的很重要...
It's really important...
ξ叶言
to me okay?
好吧
All right.
那就在@待一整天
Why don't we just hang out here all day?
有何不可
Yes why don't we?
好  多管f事先生
All right Mr. Nosey Parker.
既然你打算┪...
Seeing as you're intent on breaking my balls...
我你一}
let me ask you a question.
好
All right.
你有影像力?
Do you have a photographic memory?
不知道  我就是得
I don't know. I just kind of remember.
好比你可以得你的a
I mean how do you remember your phone number? You just do.
你念^有C化W?
Have you studied organic chemistry?
一cc
A little bit.
榱撕猛?
Oh just for fun?
榱苏啡
Yeah for kicks.
念有C化W有趣  你啦
Yeah it's so much fun studying organic chemistry. Are you mad?
你精神失常?
Have you completely lost your mind?
]人榱撕猛婺罨W
Nobody studies it for fun.
尤其δ氵@N人而言根本]必要
It's not a necessity especially for someone like you.
我@N人?
Someone like me?
rg分配o球龊途瓢傻娜
Someone who divides their time fairly evenly between batting cages and bars.
人家不f那是必要的
I would hardly say it was a necessity.
哈佛有很明的人
You know there are very smart people here at Harvard.
但他都得付出努力才能W
Even they have to study because this is really hard.
你s蔚刈龅搅  我不懂
And yet... you do it so easily. I don't understand.
我不懂你的大X怎N\作
I don't understand how your mind works.
你琴?
Did you play the piano?
eD移}
I want to talk about this.
我跟你解嘛  你?
No I'm trying to explain it to you. Do you play the piano?
一cc
Yeah a bit.
好  你看著琴就看到莫特
So when you look at a piano you see Mozart.
我看到筷子
I see "Chopsticks."
好  多芬  他一看到琴
All right well Beethoven okay? He looked at a piano
很自然地就
and it just made sense to him. He could just play.
你是f你琴?
So what are you saying? You play the piano?
根本不  望著琴...
Not a lick. I look at a piano...
我只看到琴I  踏板和木^
I see a bunch of keys three pedals and a box of wood.
但多芬  莫札特就
But Beethoven Mozart...They saw it. They could just play.
我不  B球都打不好
I couldn't paint you a picture. I probably can't hit the ball out of Fenway.
我也不琴
And I can't play the piano.
但你一小r茸龊没W作I
But you can do my O- chem paper in under an hour.
我就是那N|西
Right. Well I mean when it came to stuff like that I could always just play.
我只能解到@
That's the best I can explain it.
我有告V你
Come here. I have to tell you something.
我跟你v一件事
I have to tell you something.
不公平
It's not fair.
什N不公平?
What's not fair? What?
我在@四年了
I've been here for four years.
F在才lF你
And I've only just found you.
起a你是lF我啦
Well you found me.
你醒著?
Are you awake?
睡了
No.
你]睡
Yes you are.
跟我一起去加州
Will come to California with me.
什N?
What?
我要你跟我去加州
I want you to come to California with me.
你_定?
You sure about that?
_定
Oh yeah.
你怎N知道?
Yeah but how do you know?
不缘
I don't know.
我就是知道
I just know.
但你怎N知道?
Yeah but how do you know?
我知道  因槲腋杏X到
I know because I feel it.
你f的是很烂C的事
Because that's a really serious thing you're saying.
下Y拜到了加州...
You could be in California next week...
你可能lF不喜g我的地方
and you might find out something about me you don't like.
你希望你]f^@些...
Maybe you wish you hadn't said that...
但@是o法收回的事
but you know it's such a serious thing you can't take it back.
於是我跟不畚业娜死г诩又...
Now I'm stuck in California with someone that doesn't really want to be with me...
她s希望一切能收回
just wish they had a take- back.
什N?  什N是收回?
A what? What's a take- back?
我不想收回
I don't want a take- back.
我只要你跟我去加州
I just want you to come to California with me.
我不能去加州
Well I can't go to California with you so...
槭颤N?
Why not?
一是因槲以谶@有工作
Well one because I got a job here.
二是因槲易∵@
And two because I live here.
你不畚揖驮告V我
Look um if you don't love me you should just tell me.
我]f不勰
I'm not sayin' I don't love you.
那槭颤N不去?  你怕什N?
Then why? Why won't you come? What are you so scared of?
我怕什N?
What am I so scared of?
你不怕什N?
Well what aren't you scared of?
你活在]人挑鸬氖澜缪e...你怕要做改你的事情
You live in this safe little world where no one challenges you...
e教我  我的世界怎N
Don't tell me about my world. Don't tell me about my world.
你只是想跟低下A痈阋幌
You just want to have your little fling with the guy from the other side of town.
然後到斯坦福
Then you're gonna go off to Stanford.
你嫁o有X的混蛋
You're gonna marry some rich prick who your parents will approve of...
跟其他富家女f你到^民窟
and just sit around with the other trust fund babies and talk about how you went slummin' too once.
你在f什N?
Why are you saying this?
你楹芜@N在乎X?
What is your obsession with this money?
我十三q矢  ^承家a
My father died when I was 13 and I inherited this money.
我每天醒矶枷Ｍ能o他
You don't think every day I wake up and I wish I could give it back.
只要能我多陪他一天
That I would give it back in a second
我R上o他  但我不能
if it meant I could have one more day with him.
那是我的人生  我面λ
But I can't and that's my life and I deal with it.
e把你的害怕推到我身上
So don't put your shit on me when you're the one that's afraid.
我怕?  我他的怕什N?
I'm afraid? What am I afraid of? What the fuck am I afraid of?
你怕我  怕我不勰
You're afraid of me. You're afraid that I won't love you back.
你知道?  我也怕
You know what? I'm afraid too.
但我想看  起a我\
But fuck it I want to give it a shot. At least I'm honest with you.
y道我δ悴徽\?
I'm not honest with you?
不  你的十二哥哥呢?
No what about your 12 brothers?
你不能走  不准x_
No you're not going. You're not leaving.
你想知道什N?  我]哥哥?
What do you want to know? That I don't have 12 brothers?
我是他的孤?
That I'm a fuckin' orphan?
- 你不想的  - 我K不缘
- You don't want to hear that.  - I didn't know that.
你不想我童年被香
You don't want to hear I got fuckin' cigarettes put out on me when I was little.
我不缘
I didn't know that.
那不是手g  那混蛋刺我
That this isn't fuckin' surgery. The motherfucker stabbed me.
你不想@N事!
You don't want to hear that shit Skylar!
e跟我f你想知道!
Don't tell me you want that shit!
我想  因槲蚁湍
I do want to hear that. I want to help you.
臀?  什N鬼|西?
Help me? What the fuck?
我上有著救我?
What do I got a fuckin' sign on my back that says "Save me"?
我像要人救的幼?
Do I look like I need that?
我想跟你在一起...我勰
No I just want to be with you...I love you.
e耍我
Don't bullshit me!
e他的耍我
Don't bullshit me! Don't you fuckin' bullshit me!
我勰
I love you.
我要你f你不畚
I want to hear you say that you don't love me.
那N我就不再打o你...
Because if you say that...then I won't call you...
不再出F在你的生命e
and I won't be in your life.
我不勰
I don't love you.
很多人都o牡弥自己的天x
Most people never get to see how brilliant they can be.
因檎也坏较嘈潘的老
They don't find teachers that believe in them.
於是他深信自己很笨
They get convinced they're stupid.
希望你能感激他所做的
I hope you appreciate what he's doing
我知道他很喜g跟你合作
because I've seen how much he enjoys working with you
我]有反δ
not against you.
你好  威
Hello Will.
姆  拿c咖啡
Tom can you get us some coffee?
好
Sure.
好  我看看
Now let's see.
很好  正_
Good. This is correct.
你用了"_"
I see you used Maclaurin here.
我不知道叫什N
Yeah I don't know what you call it but...
@硬
This can't be right.
@很y堪
This would be very embarrassing.
你是否想^...
Did you ever consider...
我_信是Φ
I'm pretty sure it's right.
以後能在尚恩的k公室做?
Hey look can we do this at Sean's office from now on?
我得放下工作^  坐很
Because I got to knock off work to come here and the commute is killin' me.
好  可不可能...
Yeah sure. Did you think of the possibility...
它是Φ  Щ丶野
That's right. It's right. Just take it home with you.
尼的面怎N了?
What happened at the McNeil meeting?
我去不了  我有s
I couldn't go. I had a date.
所以我派我的判代表去
So I sent my chief negotiator.
你自己的rg致镫S你
On your own time you can do whatever you like Will.
但我安排的
But when I set up a meeting with my associates
你]出F我G
and you don't show up it reflects poorly on me.
好  那就e安排了
Then don't set up any more meetings.
我不  我取消
I won't. I'll cancel 'em.
我H自o你工作
I'll give you a job myself. I just wanted you to see what was out there.
或S我不想一子做解fT
Maybe I don't want to spend the rest of my fuckin' life explainin' shit to people.
但你可以表示感激吧
I think you could show me some appreciation.
感激?  你知道@多容易?
A little appreciation? Do you know how easy this is for me?
你知道?  e他的f笑了
Do you have any fuckin' idea how easy this is? This is a fuckin' joke.
我很z憾你不解  真的
I'm sorry you can't do this...I really am...
我不想坐在@嚎茨忝索
Because I wouldn't have to fuckin' sit here and watch you fumble around and fuck it up.
@幽憔有更多的rg喝醉?
Then you'd have more time to sit around and get drunk instead wouldn't you?
]e  @浪M我的rg
You're right. This is probably a total waste of my time.
你f得
You're right Will.
我解不出
I can't do this proof
但你  f到@
but you can. And when it comes to that
只有少等丝闯瞿阄业牟e
it's only about just a handful of people in the world who can tell the difference between you and me.
我是其中之一
But I'm one of them.
我很z憾
Sorry.
我也是
Yeah so am I.
我常希望]遇到你
Most days I wish I never met you
@游乙寡e就能睡得著
because then I could sleep at night.
不用惦有像你@拥娜
I didn't have to walk around with the knowledge that there was someone like you out there.
我不必看你糟蹋天x
I didn't have to watch you throw it all away.
比  等等
Bill hold it.
到]?
Did you hear that?
摩根!
Morgan!
如你敢在我房e看A片
If you're watchin' pornos in my mom's room again
我就揍扁你
I'm gonna give you a fuckin' beatin'!
怎N了?
What's up fellas?
要打手在你家e打  v死了
Morgan why don't you jerk off in your own fuckin' house. That's fuckin' filthy.
我家]影C
I don't have a V.C.R. in my house.
他的我不管
I don't care it.
你不用我手套打手吧
Come on. Not in my glove.
我]用手套
I didn't use the glove.
那是我的小盟手套
That's my Little League glove.
你要我怎N做
What do you want me to do?
你怎N搞的?  操棒球手套啊?
I mean what's wrong with you? You'll hump a baseball glove?
我]有  我用它清乾Q
I- I just used it for cleanup.
e在我房e打手了
Stop jerkin' off in my mother's room.
@屋e有e台影C?
Is there another V.C.R. in the house?
真可悲
It's just sad bro.
我槭颤N安局做事?
So why do you think I should work for the National Security Agency?
你⒀芯考舛丝萍
Well you'd be working on the cutting edge.
接|e看不到的科技
You'd be exposed to the kind of technology you wouldn't see anywhere else
因槎家蚜C密
because we've classified it.
混沌W  高演算法...
Superstring theory chaos math advanced algorithms.
破解密a
Code breaking.
那是其中一用
That's one aspect of what we do.
得了  那就是你做的事
Oh come on. That is what you do.
你理八成的情罅
You guys handle 80% of the intelligence workload.
是中情局的七倍大
You're seven times the size of the C.I.A.
我不喜g自F  但你fα
We don't like to brag about that Will but you're exactly right.
}不是"你致安局做事"
So the way I see it the question isn't:"Why should you work for the N.S.A.?"
而是"你楹尾蛔?"
The question is: "Why shouldn't you?"
我楹尾安局做事?
Why shouldn't I work for the N.S.A.?
很y的}
That's a tough one
我想想  若我做了
but I'll take a shot. Say I'm workin' at the N.S.A.
安局o我破解不了的密a
and somebody puts a code on my desk. Something no one else can break.
或S我了  也破解了
Maybe I take a shot at it and maybe I break it.
我很M意  因楸憩F良好
I'm real happy with myself because I did my job well.
但也S那密a...
But maybe that code...
是位於北非或中|的叛位置
was the location of some rebel army in North Africa or Middle East.
他lF後Z炸叛藏身地
Once they have that location they bomb the village where the rebels are hidin'.
陌生的一千五百人因此拭
Fifteen hundred people that I never met never had no problem with get killed.
然後政客派特鸩筷防守^
Now the politicians are saying "Send in the Marines to secure the area  "
他才不在乎
'cause they don't give a shit.
因楸簧⒌牟是他的子女
It won't be their kid over there gettin' shot
因樗都加入了後洳筷
just like it wasn't them when their number got called 'cause they were in the National Guard.
而在那中的南^孩子
It'll be some kid from Southie over there takin' shrapnel in the ass.
回後lF他以前工作的工S...
He comes back to find the plant he used to work at...
被移D到他去打仗的家
got exported to the country he got back from
害他中的橙了他的碗
and the guy who put the shrapnel in his ass got his old job...
因槟旱娜艘惶旃べY不到一元
'cause he'll work for 15 cents a day and no bathroom breaks.
最後他lF他上...
Meanwhile he realizes the only reason he was over there in the first place...
只是榱说玫皆的廉r原油
was so we could install a government that would sell us oil at a good price.
好石油公司利用恐慌
Of course the oil companies used a skirmish over there
抬高扔r  小一番
to scare up domestic oil prices. A cute little ancillary benefit for them.
但K五一加鲇屁用
but it ain't helpin' my buddy at 2.50 a gallon.
他得花rg把石油\回
They're takin' their sweet time bringin' the oil of course.
或S了一酗酒船L
Maybe they even took the liberty to hire an alcoholic skipper
他酆锐R丁尼  跟冰山玩滑雪
who likes to drink martinis and fuckin' play slalom with the icebergs.
不久他撞上冰山  原油外漏...
It ain't too long till he hits one spills the oil...
⒐獗贝笪餮蟮暮Ｑ笊物
and kills all the sea life in the North Atlantic.
F在我朋友失I  也_不起
So now my buddy's out of work he can't afford to drive
他走路去面  很y受
so he's walkin' to the fuckin' job interviews...
因榕片你慢性出血
which sucks because the shrapnel in his ass is givin' him chronic hemorrhoids.
他很I  因槊看蜗氤|西
Meanwhile he's starvin' 'cause every time he tries to get a bite to eat
唯一的特餐是北大西洋L~
the only blue plate special they're servin' is North Atlantic scrod with Quaker State.
所以  我怎N想?
So what did I think?
我有更好的c子
I'm holdin' out for somethin' better.
我乾脆射⑽遗笥阉懔
I figure fuck it. While I'm at it why not just shoot my buddy
把工作o橙  提高油r
take his job give it to his sworn enemy hike up gas prices.
Z炸村f  打死小海豹
Bomb a village club a baby seal
吸食大麻  加入後洳筷
hit the hash pipe and join the National Guard?
我可因此被x榭y
I can be elected president.
你感X孤?
You feel like you're alone?
什N?
What?
你有心`伴H?
Do you have a soul mate?
我有...?  f清楚c
Do I have a...Define that.
能蚝湍闫车娜
Somebody who challenges you.
我有查克
Uh Chuckie.
不  查克是你的家人
No Chuckie's family. He'd lie down in fuckin' traffic for you.
我v的是|幽阈撵`的人
I'm talking about someone who opens up things for you touches your soul.
我有...
I got...I got...
l?
Who?
有很多
I got plenty.
f出
Well name 'em.
莎士比  尼采  佛斯特...
Shakespeare Nietzsche Frost...
W康{  康得  洛克.
O'Connor Kant Pope Locke.
很棒  他都死了
That's great. They're all dead.
ξ叶言  他]死
Not to me they're not.
]死?  你o法和他φ
You don't have a lot of dialogue with them.
你不能回他
You can't give back to them Will.
除非你有仙丹
Not without some serious smelling salts and a heater.
那就是我所f的
That's what I'm saying.
如果你不踏出第一步...
You'll never have that kind of relationship in a world...
你^不有那NPS
where you're always afraid to take the first step
因槟阒豢吹截面的事
because all you see is every negative thing ten miles down the road.
你要[出教授架子了?
You gonna take the professor's side on this?
少跟我磉@套  ]有
Don't give me a line of shit. No.
我不想做那工作
I didn't want the job.
我不管你是否檎府工作
It's not about the job. I don't care if you work for the government.
但你能S心所欲  不受束`
But you can do anything you want. You are bound by nothing.
你凼颤N?  想要什N?
What are you passionate about? What do you want?
有人一子砌u...
There are guys who work their entire life layin' brick...
榱俗孩子碛邢衲悻F在的C
so their kids have a chance at the opportunities you have here.
我可]要求@C
I didn't ask for this.
不  你生砭陀
No. You were born with it
e逃避f你]要求
So don't cop out behind: "I didn't ask for this."
什N叫逃避?  砌u哪e不?
What do you mean cop out? What's wrong with layin' brick?
]有
Nothing.
]什N不  我w房子...
There's nothin' wrong. That's somebody's home I'm buildin'.
我爸砌u  好?
Right. My dad laid brick okay?
他拼命只钭我受教育
Busted his ass so I could have an education.
]e  那是可敬的行I
Exactly. That's an honorable profession.
修哪不?
What's wrong with fixin' somebody's car?
我人能上班  @是很光s的事
Someone will get to work the next day because of me. That's honor in that.
是的  是很光s
Yeah there is Will. There is honor in that.
搭40分火大W生...
There's honor in takin' that 40- minute train ride...
上n有乾Q的地板...
so those college kids could come in in the morning and their floors are clean.
整的桌椅也很可敬
And their wastebaskets are empty. That's real work.
That's right.
是很可敬
And that's honorable.
相信你是榱诉@份s耀才做的
I'm sure that's why you took that job. I mean for the honor of it.
我只是有小}
I just have a little question here.
你到哪e都能做工友
You could be a janitor anywhere.
楹翁糁幸涣鞯目萍W府?
Why did you work at the most prestigious technical college in the whole fuckin' world?
夜e偷偷地解算...
Why did you sneak around at night and finish other people's formulas...
世上只有人的方程式?
that only one or two people in the world could do and then lie about it?
我看不到其中的s耀
'Cause I don't see a lot of honor in that Will.
你真正想做什N?
So what do you really wanna do?
我想牧羊人
I wanna be a shepherd.
真的?
Really?
我想搬到{旭IK地放羊
I wanna move up to Nashua get a nice little spread get some sheep and tend to them.
也S你那N做
Maybe you should go do that.
什N?
What?
要自慰回家弄l衩巾搞
You know if you're gonna jerk off why don't you just do it at home with a moist towel?
你在s我?
You're chuckin' me?
出去
Yeah get the fuck outta here.
不  rg]到
No no no time's not up yet.
- _]到  - 我不走  不
- Yeah it is.  - I'm not leavin'. No.
你不回答我}  浪M我rg
You're not gonna answer you're wastin' my time.
我以槲是朋友
I thought we were friends.
[rgY束了
Playtime's over okay?
你槭颤Ns我走?
Why are you kickin' me out?
你想教我人生大道理?
You're lecturin' me on life?
看看你  糟老^
Look at you you fuckin' burnout.
是什N你^下去?
What winds your clock?
跟你合作
Workin' with you.
你的心`伴H在哪?
Where's your soul mate?
你要心`伴H  她在哪?
You wanna talk about soul mates? Where is she?
死了
Dead.
她已他的死了
That's right. She's fuckin' dead.
你就不敢再槿松下注了?
She fuckin' dies and you just cash in your chips and you walk away?
起a我玩^一把
At least I played a hand.
那你了  得很K
You played a hand and you lost. You lost a big fuckin' hand.
有些人那NK再下注
Some people will lose a big hand like that and have the sack to ante up again.
看著我  你想要什N?
Look at me. What do you wanna do?
你和你那些屁
You and your bullshit.
每人你都有狗屁答案
You got a bullshit answer for everybody.
s答不出磉@N蔚}
But I ask you a very simple question and you can't give me a straight answer
因槟悴恢道
because you don't know.
再  躲
I'll see ya Bo- peep.
去你的
Fuck you.
你是牧羊人
You're the shepherd.
牧羊人  混蛋
Shepherd. White little prick.
趁你]走打o你
I just wanted to you know um call you up uh before you left um...
我正在工作
I've been takin' all these jobs interviews and stuff
我不只I造工人
so I'm not gonna be just a construction worker.
你知道我K不在乎
Well you know I never really cared about that.
是的
Yeah.
我勰
I love you.
威?
Will?
你保重
You take care.
再
Bye.
威
Will come on. Will!
好了  做完了!
Will that's it! We're done!
我在你k公室  那孩子]
I'm sitting in your office and the boy isn't here.
十c五分了
Well it's ten past 5:00.
t到一小r十分
An hour and ten minutes late.
他不出F我就提交蟾
Well if he doesn't show up and I file a report saying he wasn't here...
他去坐牢我也不愧疚的
and he goes back to jail he won't be on my conscience.
好  很好
Okay. Fine.
怎N了?
What's up?
xx
Thanks.
真爽
Ah! God that's good.
你R子怎N?
So how's your lady?
她走了
Ah she's gone.
走?  走去哪e?
Gone? Gone where?
tW院  加州的tW院
Med school. Medical school in California.
真的?
Really?
r的事?
When was this?
一Y拜前
It was like a week ago.
好
That sucks.
Yeah.
那些r搞完?
So uh when are you done with those meetings?
^了21q的那星期
I think the week after I'm 21.
是?  他要o你工作?
They gonna hook ya up with a job or what?
往後50年要做o聊的算g
Yeah fuckin' sit in a room and do long division for the next 50 years.
可能不少X
Nah probably make some nice bank though.
我成樗的室老鼠
I'm gonna be a fuckin' lab rat.
好^@鬼|西  x_@e
Better than this shit. Way outta here.
致镒?
What do I want a way outta here for?
我下子都要住@
I mean I'm gonna fuckin' live here the rest of my life.
我居  我爸爸
You know be neighbors. You know have little kids.
一起他打小盟
Fuckin' take 'em to Little League together up Foley Field.
你是我的死h  所以e`
Look you're my best friend so don't take this the wrong way.
但20年後你如果住在@
But in 20 years if you're still livin' here
到我家看球
comin' over to my house to watch the Patriots games
在w房子  我他的⒘四
still workin' construction I'll fuckin' kill ya.
那不是恐  我宰了你
That's not a threat. That's a fact. I'll fuckin' kill ya.
你在胡扯什N?
What the fuck are you talkin' about?
你碛形]有的天x
Look you got something none of us have.
拜  楹未蠹叶歼@Nf?
Oh come on!  Why is it always this?
y道是我Σ黄鹱约?
I fuckin' owe it to myself to do this or that. What if I don't want to?
不  你]有Σ黄鹱约
No no no. Fuck you. You don't owe it to yourself.
是你Σ黄鹞
You owe it to me
因槲颐魈煨砦迨q了
'cause tomorrow I'm gonna wake up and I'll be 50
在诌@N事  o所^
and I'll still be doin' this shit. That's all right. That's fine.
而你已碛邪偃f券
I mean you're sittin' on a winnin' lottery ticket.
sC囊的不敢冬F  狗屁
You're too much of a pussy to cash it in and that's bullshit.
我不惜一切交Q你所碛械
'Cause I'd do fuckin' anything to have what you got.
其他@些人也是
So would any of these fuckin' guys.
你再待20年是侮辱我
Be an insult to us if you're still here in 20 years.
C在@e是浪M你rg
Hangin' around here is a fuckin' waste of your time.
你懂什N?
You don't know that.
我不懂?
I don't know that?
你不懂
No. You don't know that.
我告V你我懂什N
Oh I don't know that. Let me tell you what I do know.
我每天到你家接你
Every day I come by your house and I pick you up.
我出去喝酒笑[  那很棒
We go out and have a few drinks and few laughs and it's great.
但我一天中最棒的r刻
You know what the best part of my day is?
只有十秒
It's for about ten seconds:
耐＼龅侥慵议T口
from when I pull up to the curb and when I get to your door.
每次我敲T都希望你不在了
'Cause I think maybe I'll get up there and I'll knock on the door and you won't be there.
不f再  什N都]有
No "good- bye  " no "see ya later." No nothing.
就@N走了
You just left.
我懂得不多  但我很清楚
I don't know much but I know that.
真是y  我你⑴c...
This is a disaster Sean. I brought you in here...
是要你瓦@孩子  不是s走他
because I wanted you to help me with the boy not to run him out.
我知道怎N付他
I know what I'm doing with the boy.
我不管你跟他有什N默契
I don't care if you have a rapport with the boy!
我不在乎你花我的X_心
I don't care if you have a few laughs even at my expense.
但你敢破奈业氖驴纯
But don't you dare undermine what I'm trying to do here.
破?
Undermine?
@孩子目前很脆弱
This boy is at a fragile point right now.
我t解他很脆弱  好?
I do understand. He is at a fragile point.
他有些}
He's got problems.
他有什N}?
What problems does he have?
工友或坐牢比^好?
That he's better off as a janitor in jail?
跟一群智障在一起比^好?
Better hanging out with a bunch of retarded gorillas?
你想他槭颤N那N做?
Why do you think he does that?
你缘槭颤N?
You have any fuckin' clue why?
他能付}
He can handle the problems.
付工作  @然也付你了
He can handle the work. He obviously handled you.
我f
Listen to me.
他楹味惚?  楹尾恍湃稳?
Why is he hiding? Why doesn't he trust anybody?
因樗的遭遇
Because the first thing that happened to him
他被鬯的人z
he was abandoned by the people who were supposed to love him the most.
e跟我v佛洛伊德的屁
Don't give me that Freudian crap.
他槭颤N跟你所^的智障混?
Why does he hang out with those retarded gorillas as you call them?
因槿绻他叫他扁你
Because any one of them if he asked them to
他照k  那叫做x
would take a bat to your head. That's called loyalty.
是喔  很感人
Yeah that's very touching.
他付l了?
Who's he handling?
他在e人x_之前先s人走
He pushes people away before they have a chance to leave him.
那是防l心理  好?
It's a defense mechanism all right?
他因此孤了20年
For 20 years he's been alone because of that.
你F在逼他  事情重演
If you push him right now it's gonna be the same thing all over again.
我不他重蹈覆H
I'm not gonna let that happen to him.
e那N做
Don't you do that.
什N?
What?
e他J榉或失]PS
Don't infect him with the idea that it's okay to quit that it's okay to be a failure.
^τ嘘PS!
Because it's not okay Sean!
如果你是馕页晒...
And if you're angry at me for being successful for being what you could have been...
我]饽
I'm not angry at you.
你有  你憎何
Oh yes you're angry at me.
我不因槌晒ο蚰阗r不是
You resent me but I'm not gonna apologize for any success I've had.
你馕易龅侥惚砟茏龅降氖
You're angry at me for doing what you could have done!
你行淖
But ask yourself Sean...Ask yourself...
你要威有那N感受?
if you want Will to feel that way...
你要他感X像失≌?
if you want him to feel like a failure?
你@自大狂!
You arrogant shit!
我不去同W的原因
That's why I don't come to the goddamn reunions
是因槭懿涣四愕难凵
'cause I can't stand that look in your eye.
那N屈尊y堪的眼神
That condescending embarrassed look.
你J槲沂  我有自知之明
You think I'm a failure. I know who I am.
我樽约焊械津傲
I'm proud of what I do.
那是自X的x
It was a conscious choice.
我]搞砸!
I didn't fuck up!
你和你朋友J槲液芸z
And you and your cronies think I'm some sort of pity case.
你和你那些狗屁n程
You and your kiss- ass chorus...
你老是提自己的菲德章...
following you around going "The Field's medal!"
你怎N是@N怕失?
Why are you still so fuckin' afraid of failure?
你是嫉妒我有章?
It's about my medal isn't it?
天哪  我回家拿o你  送o你好了
Oh God I could go home and get it for you. You can have it.
拜不要
Oh please don't.
把章塞M你的屁眼e
Shove the medal up your fuckin' ass all right?
因槲也辉诤跄愕莫章
'Cause I don't give a shit about your medal
因槲以谀氵]上W之神前就JR你了
because I knew you before you were a mathematical god
早在你M青春痘  思l...
when you were pimple- faced and homesick...
不知要尿在床的那一^的r候
and didn't know what side of the bed to piss on.
是  你^去F在都比我明
Yeah you were smarter than me then and you're smarter than me now.
你人生成@e怪我
So don't blame me for how your life turned out.
我]怪你!  @跟你oP!
I don't blame you! It's not about you!
你@W混球!  是P於那孩子!
You mathematical dick! It's about the boy!
他是好孩子!  我不看著你...
He's a good kid! And I won't see you...
像F在糟蹋我般糟蹋他
fuck him up like you're tryin' to fuck up me right now.
他也感X是失≌!
I won't see you make him feel like a failure too!
他不失!
He won't be a failure!
但你如果逼他!
But if you push him! If you ride him!
我能有今天成就是逼出淼
I am what I am today because I was pushed and because I learned to push myself.
他不是你!  你懂!
He's not you! You get that!
我待再
I can come back.
不  M  我正要走
No come in. Uh I was just leaving.
他和我之g的年往事
A lot of that stuff goes back a long way between me and him.
跟你oP
You know. Not about you.
那是什N?
What is that?
你的n案
This is your file.
我要送回去o法官u估
I have to send it back to the judge for evaluation.
你不我失“?
Oh. Hey you're not gonna fail me are you?
e面怎N?
What's it say?
你想看?
Wanna read it?
槭颤N?
Why?
你有^那N?
Have you had any uh experience with that?
20年的o
Twenty years of counseling.
我看^很K的事
Yeah I've seen some pretty awful shit.
你有那方面的?
I mean have you had any experience with that?
人的?
Personally?
是的
Yeah.
我有
Yeah I have.
肯定不好
It sure ain't good.
我爸是酒鬼  醉如泥
My father was an alcoholic. Mean fuckin' drunk.
他喝醉回家就想打人
He'd come home hammered lookin' to whale on somebody.
我激怒他以保o和弟弟
So I'd provoke him so he wouldn't go after my mother and little brother.
他若晚上Чぞ呋砭途彩了
Interesting nights when he wore his rings.
他把扳手  棍子和皮[桌上
He used to just put a wrench a stick and a belt on the table.
然後f"x一"
Just say "Choose."
我挑皮
Well I gotta go with the belt there.
我通常挑扳手
I used to go with the wrench.
槭颤N是扳手?
Why the wrench?
因槭"操他的"
'Cause fuck him that's why.
你B父?
Your foster father?
怎N?
Yeah. So uh what is it.
是不是威有"依附情Y"?
Like Will has an attachment disorder? Is it all that stuff?
害怕被z?
Fear of abandonment?
那是我跟史Pm分手的原因?
Is that why I broke up with Skylar?
我不缘媚分手了
I didn't know you had.
分手了
Yeah I did.
想?
You wanna talk about it?
不想
No.
威  我知道的不多
Hey Will I don't know a lot.
但你看到@]?
You see this?
@些事
All this shit?
不是你的e
It's not your fault.
是  我知道
Yeah I know that.
看著我  孩子  不是你的e
Look at me son. It's not your fault.
我知道
I know.
不是你的e
No. It's not your fault.
我知道
I know.
你不知道  不是你的e
No no you don't. It's not your fault.
我知道
I know.
不是你的e
It's not your fault.
好
All right.
不是你的e
It's not your fault.
e整我
Don't fuck with me all right?
不是你的e
It's not your fault.
e整我好?  不要是你
Don't fuck with me Sean not you.
不是你的e
It's not your fault.
我的天...真Σ黄
My God...My God! I'm so sorry! My God!
去他的  好?
Fuck them okay?
有什N事?
Can I help you?
我是威杭汀  我碚工作
Yeah I'm Will Hunting. I'm here about a position.
坐一下
Could you just have a seat for a moment?
你x衲囊?
Which one did you take?
尼那
I was over at McNeil.
教授臀野才诺墓ぷ髦一
It's one of the jobs the professor set me up with.
我]告V他  我和老^...
I haven't told him yet but I went down there and talked to my boss...
新老人好像不e
My new boss. He seemed like a good guy.
那是你要的?
Is that what you want?
我想是吧
Yeah you know I think so.
做得好  恭喜
Well good for you. Congratulations.
xx
Thanks.
rg到了
Time's up.
就@?  我Y束了
So that's...So that's it? So we're done?
就@
Yeah that's it.
你Y束了  自由了
You're done. You're a free man.
我想跟你f  我...
Well um I just want you to know Sean that...
不客
You're welcome Will.
希望我保持j
So you know I hope we keep in touch you know.
我也希望
Yeah me too.
我旅行一子  有cy
I'll be travelin' around a bit. It'll be a little hard but uh...
不^我有答C  我查
I've got an answering machine at the college I'll be checking in with.
拿著
So here's the number.
你打  我R上回
You call that. I'll get back to you right away.
我要再下注...
Yeah you know I figured I'm just gonnan put my money back on the table...
看@次到什N
and see what kind of cards I get.
你跟著心走就]事了
You do what's in your heart son. You'll be fine.
xx你  尚恩
Thank you Sean.
xx你  威
Thank you Will.
@`反t病人PS?
Hey does this violate the patient- doctor relationship?
除非你抓我屁股
Naw. Only if you grab my ass.
保重
Take care.
你也是
You too.
祝你好\  孩子
Good luck son.
善科【
Two beers.
你去了?
What's up? Did you guys go?
]有  我得裢怂
No. I had to talk him down.
你怎N不管管他?
Why didn't you yoke him?
摩根有一堆屁
Little Morgan's got a lot of scrap to him.
天天有人想扁他  他不步
People try to whip his ass every week. Fuckin' kid won't back down.
v我什N?
What are you sayin' about me?
我跟你v?  帜闫ㄊ
Was I talkin' to you? None of your fuckin' business.
臀遗啤酒
Go get me a beer.
我叫了善
I ordered two beers!
蛋
Hey asshole.
致?  v
What bitch?
生日快
Happy birthday.
以槲忘了?  v
Thought we forgot huh bitch?
- 我去  - 我去
- Come on!  - I'm goin'. I'm goin'.
l先?
All right. Who's first?
- 戆苫斓  - l先?
- Come on motherfucker!  - Who's first?
丹尼男孩
Oh Danny boy
你的Y物
Here's your present.
快c
Come on bro.
你的新工作要在砘
Well we knew you had to get back and forth to Cambridge for your new job.
我不每天d你  所以...
I knew I wasn't gonna fuckin' drive you every day so...
摩根想o你I免票C
Morgan wanted to get you a "T" pass.
我]那Nf
That's not what I was sayin'!
- 但你21q了  - 可以合法喝酒
- But uh you're 21 now.  - You're legally allowed to drink.
我想最好的Y物就是子
So we figured the best thing for ya was a car.
喜g?
How do you like it?
@是...
This is like...
我@子看^最h的
It's the ugliest fuckin' car I've ever seen in my life.
快  兄弟
Come on brother.
你怎N弄的?
How'd you guys do this?
我和比一起搜括零件
You know me and Bill scraped together the parts
摩根每天出去乞零X
and Morgan was out panhandlin' for change every day.
身都是我搞的
I had the router to do all the bodywork.
弄得他的棒呆了
Yeah I have a fuckin' job too brother.
他┝宋赡暌工作
Guy's been up my ass for two years about a job.
得他做褪
I had to let him help with the car.
你K於有工作了?  摩根
So you finally got a job huh Morgan?
有^一  F在又]了
Yeah had one. Now I'm fucked again.
是什N工作?  除草工人?
So what is it? A lawn mower? What do ya got?
我和比重新打造引擎
Me and Bill rebuilt this engine ourselves here.
@是v好  引擎不e
It's a good car. The engine's good. Engine's good.
生日快  威
Happy 21 Will.
21q生日快  兄弟
Happy 21 brother.
M
Come on in.
尚恩  我...
Sean l um...
我也是
Me too Gerry.
那就好
Yeah. Good.
f你要假
I heard you're takin' some time.
我想旅行一子
Yeah. Travel a little bit.
或S
Maybe write.
去哪e?
So where are you going?
印度  中和巴的摩
India and China and Baltimore.
你知道r回?
You know when you'll be back?
知道  我前商焓盏
Oh. I got this flyer the other day.
上面f半年後_同W
It says uh class of '72 is having a reunion in six months.
是  我也收到一
Yeah I got one of those too.
你戆  我你喝酒
Why don't you come? I'll buy ya a drink.
那N龊系木剖敲赓M的
The drinks at those things are free.
我知道  我在S刺
I know Gerry. I was being ironical.
F在喝一杯怎N?
How about a drink right now?
好啊  好主意
Yeah. It's a good idea.
走  @杯我
Come on. This one's on me.
我@有中的彩票
I got the winner right here pal.
就是@
Yes sir this is the one.
通往天堂的票
This is my ticket to paradise.
你知道彩券中的C率?
Do you know what the odds are against winning the lottery?
四比一?
What? Four to one?
三千f比一
About 30 million to one.
是有C
I still have a shot you know?
跟F在被W糁械C率一
Yes just about as big chance as you being hit by lightning here on the staircase right now.
那也有可能...
It's a possibility too. I mean 32 million. If you look at the size...
威!
Will!
威?
Will?
他不在
He's not there.
尚恩
Sean.
如果教授起工作的事
If the professor calls about that job.
跟他f抱歉  我要去找女孩
just tell him sorry I had to go see about a girl.
威
Will.
@小混蛋  偷我的?
Son of a bitch. He stole my line.